CP Wong | NTU: Hey, Jermaine.
germayne: Hey, hello.
germayne: Hey, hey, Erwin. Hello.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, just to introduce, Elvin.
CP Wong | NTU: Meet Jermaine, Jermaine, Alvin. Can you hear me, Alvin?
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): Yeah, yeah, Ken Ken, hi.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay, good.
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): You can hear me also.
CP Wong | NTU: Yes, loud and clear.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah.
CP Wong | NTU: So, yeah, so Elvin is gonna be, supporting, supporting the cohort, for Module 3.
CP Wong | NTU: And, yeah, you guys will be meeting him on Saturday lah, so I… I… I will… I will wait until Saturday lah, then you can make a proper intro. Yeah, so in the meantime, yeah, just…
CP Wong | NTU: Just make him feel comfortable.
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): I thought it's my job to make you all feel comfortable.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, just welcome lah. I think, Jamin…
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, a little soon to be coming in, yeah.
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): Meh.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay, I think…
CP Wong | NTU: Jamie, you will usually pass co-hosts too soon, right?
germayne: Yep, yep, yep. I realized I was muted.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay, good.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay.
CP Wong | NTU: Hey, Noel.
CP Wong | NTU: Hi, JR.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Good evening, everyone.
CP Wong | NTU: I…
Easwaran Jayaraman: There's the big baby.
CP Wong | NTU: Hey, hello. Hi, Kiming.
Kim Meng Phoa: Hello.
Kim Meng Phoa: Oh, by the way, I… for the last week of the, Module 3, I will be in Hong Kong.
Kim Meng Phoa: Okay. Okay, so I will lock in, but I may not be able to… I will lock in and do the attendance and listen to the lesson, but it may not be able to talk, because I may be walking around.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, it's okay, no problem. Yeah, thanks for informing, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, thanks.
CP Wong | NTU: So, if you guys didn't know, right,
CP Wong | NTU: the recordings are available until learner, so… Yeah.
CP Wong | NTU: So you can go to media, you can go to the media gallery. Usually, I will upload, I will upload and end the week lah. Okay.
CP Wong | NTU: Hi, Hitesh, Jagar.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: ICP.
CP Wong | NTU: Hey, Daniel.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): I see people.
CP Wong | NTU: Yes, you're welcome, Edwin.
CP Wong | NTU: Bye soon!
Soon | NTU: Hello, CP.
CP Wong | NTU: Hey, how are you?
Soon | NTU: It's, Albinian?
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, Elvin, this is the… Elvin Ang. Elvin, second Elvin.
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): So…
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah.
CP Wong | NTU: A bit soon.
Dr Alvin Ang (2nd device): Hello.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay, I think I'll leave your tweet lah.
CP Wong | NTU: So I'll… I'll just mute myself, Jermaine, anytime.
germayne: Oh, I thought you wanted to do the introduction.
CP Wong | NTU: Nola, I think I will… I will let Elvin do the introduction… intro himself on Saturday.
germayne: Okay.
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah.
CP Wong | NTU: Face-to-face, yeah.
germayne: Okay, I think then we can…
CP Wong | NTU: Yeah, it can just proceed lah, yeah.
germayne: It's at this.
CP Wong | NTU: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so those… See you guys. Yeah, yeah, see you, see you. Okay, so those of you, if you are in… if you are not convenient, traveling on the way, commuting, then I think it's okay. You guys… you guys can turn on the camera whenever you are ready.
germayne: Okay, so before I start, just wanted to call out, right, for the… for the Kaggle, I think, I think quite, quite good job. I've been… I've been monitoring the…
germayne: the… I'll just, I'll just share that, okay, in case you guys don't know.
germayne: Okay, so I'll just share my screen, so if you can see my screen. I think… I think quite good… quite good job on all the teams. The… the placing has been shuffering between the first three teams. Actually, the first four teams. The first four teams are essentially changing non-stop every day. So please continue to… continue to work hard.
germayne: the placement is not permanent. Essentially.
germayne: the placing is actually changing non-stop, so which means that you guys are actually submitting and thinking about how to approach the problem. I would say… I would say good for the remaining three teams.
germayne: Please continue to submit more, right?
germayne: I believe you should be able to close the gap.
germayne: Okay? So, on Saturday, probably I can just give more advice and more tips, so that you guys can maybe make use of some of my advice to go further.
germayne: Okay? But please continue to keep up. Maybe for the winner, we will have a few sponsored items.
germayne: I think maybe I'm the one sponsoring, but… but regardless, the reward should be just for fun, so, please, please continue to…
germayne: strive for first placement, and then we will have time to work on this on Saturday.
germayne: Okay, so I think I'll just get started. Maybe I'll just wait one more minute for people to come in, then I'll get started.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so for today, right, we will be transiting away from supervised learning. Essentially, we talk a bit about the basic
germayne: traditional machine learning algorithms for supervised learning. We will revisit supervised learning later on, after this week. For now, we are taking a small
germayne: Stop on supervised learning and move on to unsupervised learning.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, you can see we are…
germayne: halfway, to be honest. We are halfway through this course of Module 3. So at this point, you know, you guys should not be shy about asking questions or, you know, asking me any questions or even participating in class. We are actually halfway through. So in a blink of an eye, you guys would finish Module 3.
germayne: Thursday, we will talk a bit about time series. It's sort of a different paradigm, also a bit more from the traditional statistical model perspective. Then, next week, we will go on to neural networks and deep learning.
germayne: And we will focus more on the building blocks for deep learning. And on Thursday next week, we'll talk a bit about computer vision, which is an extension from
germayne: Deep learning, and you will see that, again, we are just extending the building block in order to think about reasoning on
germayne: three-dimensional data space, right? Or even more than that. So essentially, we will see, and we'll discuss this application for computer vision and neural network next week.
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think from a, from a roadmap perspective, we are going on to supervised learning. So essentially, today, we will just talk a bit about, you know, two, two, two topics.
germayne: I think the first topic is more on dimensionality reduction. It's not really unsupervised learning, but it's a bit more about how do we actually process the features, right, in terms of, like, the input data.
germayne: So, we will first talk about dimension reduction, then we'll talk about unsupervised learning. And if you think about unsupervised learning, essentially, it's how do we actually cluster data. So, the essence is that
germayne: using unsupervised learning algorithms, you will be able to partition your data without the need of having any target label, right? But for the entirety of last week.
germayne: We actually saw that supervised learning, we require some kind of target label in order for the algorithms to partition the data in order to estimate the target labels.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Bitter?
germayne: Okay. So, so for today, there's two main topics. We'll talk a bit about dimensionality reduction.
germayne: in terms of processing your features. We'll talk a bit about the motivation of why do we actually need to do that, and we'll introduce a few examples of this transformation that we could be applying to dimension… to do… to perform dimensionality reduction.
germayne: Of course, to reduce dimension from your data is not just
germayne: is not… it's not just strictly restricted to what we are teaching today. Actually, later on, when we go through deep learning next week, I briefly will also show you guys that deep learning algorithms also can perform dimensionality reduction.
germayne: The second part, and after we are done with the lecture for dimensionality reduction, soon we'll go through the notebook, and once we are done with the notebook, we'll come back again to unsupervised learning, and we'll go through some very common clustering algorithms, and then after that, we will end the class by going to the notebooks.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I want to talk a bit about some… some high-level overview for why do we want to reduce the dimension. So, you can really think about dimensionality reduction. It's really just a way to process your features, right, your input data. And it's really, really…
germayne: Thought, in a sense whereby it's important for us to, one, to reduce the dimension.
germayne: Right, and when we think about reducing dimension, mathematically, you are really just thinking about
germayne: Having some kind of mapping where you just want to reduce your data set.
germayne: from a higher dimension to a smaller dimension. So it is really just, if you think about it, if you have some kind of real number… okay, so pardon for my ugly handwriting. So what you want is, you just want to map your data from N, right? You just want to map it
germayne: from N to, let's say, a real number, M, and usually you want your dimension space where M is actually smaller than n, right? So, the point here is that if you realize in the Kaggle data that was provided, you have… you are given
germayne: a huge number of input features, right? And when you start to do more feature engineering, actually you realize that your feature sets can actually grow beyond 77 features.
germayne: without… without exposing all the secret ingredient from your group, right, can I maybe just understand from the… from the class?
germayne: did anybody end up with high number of features for your group? I mean, you're not really exposing a secret, right? But anybody actually ended up working with more than what was given.
germayne: Nobody willing to say anything.
germayne: So, so you mean everybody has smaller features? Who has more, actually? Who ended up more? Just, just give me a show of hands.
germayne: Who ended up… okay, whether you use it or not is a separate question, but actually, who explored and ended up with more than the given?
germayne: Nobody.
germayne: Okay, so some, some.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So you realize that when you start to engineer features, you have the… okay, anyway, you guys are way too competitive, right? I'm not saying anything. But… okay, but the whole idea here is that sometimes you do have a lot of input data, and I'm going to share with you some motivations on why
germayne: why it's actually important. And today, we'll talk a bit mainly about one of the techniques, which is what we call the principal component analysis. You will see later, it's a linear transformation.
germayne: I won't really cover too much about TISNI. Tisney, I will give some resources for you guys to read, but we'll focus mainly on principle component analysis, and you basically want to see that
germayne: These techniques, essentially, these algorithms, this transformation, basically aims to find some kind of mapping where you're transforming your data from a higher dimension to a smaller dimension.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think I'm just going to go through some of the things here. So, from a… from a… from an intuition perspective.
germayne: When your number of features actually increase, you need a larger number of data to actually generalize the… the…
germayne: the input space. I will show some… I will show some illustration later, right, to let you illustrate that, actually, when you think about higher dimension, the number of data required to fill in the data space actually increases exponentially, okay?
germayne: And of course, you start to realize that if you just have way too many features, there are some features that might be noise. So this actually falls into the realm of
germayne: feature selection, right? So, in a certain sense, what dimensionality reduction aims to also do is that maybe, perhaps by projecting certain transformation from a higher dimensional space to a smaller dimensional space, you might be able to select
germayne: you know, certain kinds of selection, you might be able to tweak certain knobs in order to reduce the noise, okay?
germayne: And of course, the last thing, which is also true, is that
germayne: I think I mentioned to you guys that
germayne: as human beings, you can only visualize three dimensions, right? If anybody can visualize more than three, please let me know, right? But the idea here is that typically, if you have some kind of higher dimensional data, you will want to
germayne: project them to a smaller dimension so that you can visualize, right? Either in two-dimensional space or three-dimensional space.
germayne: Okay? Because beyond that, as human beings, we cannot really
germayne: interpret higher dimensions. So what you want to do is you want to perform some kind of transformation.
germayne: You want to have some kind of constraints where you want to maintain the relationship of the data, not to change it too much, and visualize them in two-dimensional space.
germayne: So what you can see here is that if you… if you imagine one of the algorithms that we taught you, last week… was it last week? Yeah, last week.
germayne: if you remember from KNN perspective, right, if you have one single dimension, if you imagine, in a KNN perspective, let's say you just only need 5 blocks of data to represent
germayne: a certain data space, right? If I were to think about this data in two dimensions, you realize that, essentially, it becomes
germayne: 5 times 5, right? 25.
germayne: And if I were to think about this in three-dimensional space, the number of data points essentially becomes 5 to the power of 3.
germayne: Correct? So, the idea here is that when you think about
germayne: higher dimension, you essentially need much more data to represent the data space. If you think about this in KNN, you can see that this really grows exponential, right? For every dimension you're adding.
germayne: you're not increasing linearly. The number of data in order to best represent this same space increases exponentially. So that is the intuition we give for curse of dimensionality.
germayne: Okay? So, one technique today that we will spend some time talking about is a linear transformation, very, very common transformation.
germayne: That we can be performing.
germayne: And because it's linear, of course, there are some assumptions taken. But the idea here is that we want to project these data, it's a linear transformation, we want to project them into some kind of linear combination of features, okay? And what this does, from a data perspective.
germayne: Is that the projection will actually project it… project your data in the direction that we want to maximize the variance.
germayne: Right? So you can see here, right, it's actually the greatest variance. And the intuition of why we want the variance is that we actually want to spread the data, we want to have this component, where if we are able to spread the data
germayne: Out maximally, right, with the larger spread, then essentially we are able to capture the necessary information from the data itself.
germayne: Okay? So what this means is that, from a graphical perspective.
germayne: If I just have a graph, Right? And suppose if I…
germayne: want to project the data, so let's say this is the new data that I'm projecting, Right.
germayne: And if the final projection
germayne: is actually able to… so this is the component that I projected, right? So imagine my data is 10 dimensions. Now, if I project them to 2 dimension, and
germayne: this is the first component that I'm actually projecting my data to, and if actually I'm able to have a good projection such that the data is well spread out, then essentially I'm able to segregate this data and capture all the information to separate the data, right? So that's actually the idea.
germayne: And, and one, one, one more…
germayne: characteristic of PCA is also that each of the components are orthogonal. So basically, orthogonal just looks something like that, right? So this is the second component. And the idea here is that if you remember the operation that I mentioned.
germayne: You always want your new projection to be smaller than your current projection, right? So if, let's say, you have 10 features, which is in 10 dimensions, 10D, I will always want to find a projection where it's less than 10. And what PCA does is that it projects them linearly.
germayne: Right? Such that the first component would have the maximum variance.
germayne: Now, I want to ask you guys, if you look at the first component.
germayne: If you think about maximum variance, and I'm drawing this line.
germayne: What does it… what actually does it remind you guys of?
germayne: Anybody remember anything?
Zac Ang: Mr. Jaws.
germayne: Yeah, correct. So, actually, you would think that, oh, actually.
germayne: this is very similar to your OLS, right? And actually, coincidentally, right, I mean, rather, not coincidentally, in the component that maximizes the maximum variance, it's actually the direction… the component actually also reduces the sum of squares.
germayne: So you can see that there's some… actually some kind of relation that is very, very similar to your linear regression.
germayne: Okay? So the intuition here, right, I want you guys to again take away, is that you want your component, right.
germayne: And… and… So you want to find a mapping where PCA actually maps
germayne: the data from M dimension back to M dimension, where M dimension, you get to select this M dimension to be… has to be smaller than your original dimension. And you will see later that this M components, or this M number of projection, these M components.
germayne: The first component will always be the one that has the maximum, the largest variance, in order to explain the data.
germayne: Right? So what this means is that the larger the variance, the more the component is able to spread out the data, the better it is, because it captures more information, right? And the idea is that if I'm able to separate them nicely, as far as possible, right.
germayne: This, this, this data point is not my, by the way, right, this dot is not my original data, this is essentially my new representation of the data. If I'm able to separate them very far away, it means that I'm able to capture the information needed. Because if you think about it.
germayne: Again, the intuition is that if all the data is actually all clumped up together, basically, I don't have enough context to separate them, right? It's not a good thing. You want to… you want to find features that is able to distinguish each data point as far as possible, right? Think about it from your resil flat data prediction. If your X values are
germayne: making all the data cluttered together is not… it's not useful, right? I want to find information that is able to spread them out as far as possible, able to distinguish them.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So what this means is that
germayne: you realize that high variance is actually a good thing later on, right? We want to find a mapping where it maximizes the variance
germayne: Right, and we will see later how that is important. So what PCA does, again, right, is that it's a linear transformation, which means that it has some assumptions underlying, which assumes that
germayne: the… the components actually have some kind of linear relationship. If, of course, if it's non-linear, all of your features, if they are nonlinear, right, in terms of the relationship, then obviously PCA will not work out.
germayne: Okay? And I'll show you guys how to actually see this later. Okay?
germayne: Okay, I'll stop here first.
germayne: Anybody has any question?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Oh, yes, yes.
germayne: Okay, Zach, what does that mean?
germayne: Is that, is that it?
germayne: Are you saying something?
Zac Ang: Yeah, I thought that… Because you say the variance bigger means good, so…
Zac Ang: The loss function, it's like your… the linear regression. The loss function is bigger than is better, correct?
germayne: Okay, in this case, right, in this case, they have a different loss function, per se. It's not about predicting, but the idea is that I want to find a projection where after I project, each data point
germayne: is actually very spread out in terms of the data point, not in terms of to the line. I think what you're thinking about was previously you're thinking about predicting, right? But here, it's not. Here, when I say maximum variance, you can see, right, maximum variance in a sense whereby I want all the dots to be spread out.
germayne: far apart.
germayne: After the transformation. If I'm transforming the data, and the data is all clumped up together, essentially that's a bad… that's a bad projection.
germayne: If you understand what I'm saying. So if, let's say, your data is in 10 dimensions, and if I project them, and everybody's data is ended up like that.
germayne: That's a… that's a bad thing, intuitively.
germayne: Correct? Because the information… I'm not capturing enough information to differentiate all these points. But if I'm having a lot of information, if I'm capturing the essence, let's say, of 41, 40 of you guys.
germayne: I'm actually having enough information to group everybody separately, if you think about it, right? And of course, that's what I mean by maximum variance. But if you talk about the MSC, it's getting confusing, because internally, PCA has this reconstruction error, and of course, it wants to minimize the reconstruction error. But…
germayne: Not going to talk about that, but the takeaway here is that you want to find a new representation of your data where the first component, at least, has the best
germayne: Variance, where it's actually able to spread the data out.
germayne: as far as possible. And if you think about it, right, you want your features to have this spread, because if you want to put it into your model, having this spread basically allows me to classify or group them into different things, right? If, let's say, I want to project them using the features that you have from your residual flat value.
germayne: I would want all this input data to spread them out as far as possible. Oh, maybe houses. Of course, you can't interpret the components.
germayne: After that, but the idea is that if I'm inputting some magic features into my ratio value, my ratio house, like, for example, things like the location of the house, then basically I want to spread the data out very far apart from each other, correct?
germayne: Correct? Houses in orchard versus houses in Drong versus houses in Sambawang and stuff. Basically, I want some component that spreads them very far apart.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Buh… Yeah, I, I was, I was thinking that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because linear regression is like a line, right? If the number… if the points are all close together.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then your line will capture more, so you can predict better.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, is it, like, you know, it depends on what model you are using.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I don't know, I… I mean.
germayne: No, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Great.
germayne: So, if you really think about it, right, okay, I think we are digressing, but the idea here is that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah.
germayne: If I want to… if I want to make a prediction, right? Okay, so here's the intuition, okay, we are going… we are digressing a bit. The idea is that if I want to make some kind of prediction.
germayne: having things that allows me to group and cut them is very important. It means that the input feature is important. So let's say, for example, let's say, for example.
germayne: I want to build, okay, let's say in the case of the Rio flat.
germayne: you have… you want… your goal is to actually predict different buckets of flat, right? So maybe you have, you have Y1, you have Y2, you have Y3, and you have Y4.
germayne: A good feature, by definition, is one that allows you to separate all of them. Agree?
germayne: So, for example, if you think that… if you think that…
germayne: a good indicator to predict a house is the location. Then location… the location variable must be able to split the data into different partitions, correct?
germayne: You guys can follow, right? So, for example, for example, let's say, your intuition is that actually the location matters.
germayne: Then having this variable, it should split my data out into different groups, right?
germayne: A useless variable is one where you put in the variable, it doesn't tell me anything, it just tells me everybody is still the same. That's by definition useless, right? There's no information for me. So then, the intuition here is that
germayne: A good variable, a good X, must be one that helps you cut them nicely. Of course, cut them in a way where, A, actually, all of them are able to group them.
germayne: Into different, similar values.
germayne: Does that make sense, Nora?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Right? So the intuition here is that being able to split data up is a good thing, it's not a bad thing.
germayne: And the intuition here must be, like, let's say the location, right? If you think about it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Crazy, happy people.
germayne: Yeah?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I agree that explaining data so that you… is… is definite, you know, like, oh, this is A, this is B, this apple is always good. But, but I thought that question was also quite,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: quite intuitive also, because, like, you know, when it comes to linear regression, let's say we have a line, or a curve, or whatever. You know, we want to line to cover as many points as possible, so that it can do better prediction.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So when you have PC down here trying to split it up, right, are you saying that
Low Keng Teck, Noel: you know, needle regression, you know, like, I mean, the intuitive for needle regression is, like, if the line can cut, cover as many, as many points, so the points are very close to one another. Now we have PCA, right, which is like, you know, you know where you're coming from? Because it's like, if the PCA was to split everything up, then the line will have problems getting all of them, then we'd be like…
germayne: reputation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Very bay, right?
germayne: The big difference here is that when you do linear regression, you are finding a mapping that maps F of X to Y. So what I want is, I want F of X to be very close to Y. So, which means that the difference between Y and my Y hat, the prediction, needs to be close.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: what I'm doing here is I'm not finding F of X. I'm mapping… I'm mapping X to a new mapping, X prime.
germayne: where I'm not losing enough information, but this new X prime, I'm just trying to say one of the components, the first one, is one that is able to separate the data points out as far as possible. It's very, very different.
germayne: this is… we are talking about a different thing, right? This one, we are talking about the residual, where if I want to fit a line, I want the line to have the closest gap between all my dots.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Here, I'm talking about spreading the dots out. Nothing to do with the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So after PCA, my… will my… let's say, will my prediction be, let's say, with linear regression, would it be better, or…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: that depends.
germayne: Depends. That depends. That is an empirical thing that you can try out. So after I tell you guys today.
germayne: You guys are free to try out PCA in your… in your Kaggle, okay? You guys are free to try out. The only thing that you are restricted is the algorithms.
germayne: Okay? But today, you guys learned about PCA. You want to know whether it works, you try it empirically.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, that's good to know. I was thinking whether I could use that.
germayne: you guys can use that. Anything, if in doubt, please ask me, okay? I can say that you guys can use it, because it's not a new supervised learning model, it's fine.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so I'll talk about… okay, I think I've sort of, like, really talked about this. I think the idea here is that a lot of this algorithm tries to compress the data, and if you think about it, right, you want to compress data as much as possible, right? It's just like, if you think about, traditionally for a lot of other engineering aspects, when people want to compress.
germayne: information, want to compress data, I want to compress music.
germayne: you want to find some kind of compression where you want to compress as much information as possible without losing things, right? If, let's say, movie or music, you try to compress the file, you might be losing some kind of information, or maybe the quality became worse. Same thing here.
germayne: For PCA, when you do a compression, you will have an option later, soon we'll show you guys later, that you have the decision to make
germayne: to choose how much information you want, right? And I'll show you guys later, graphically. And the idea is that, of course, there's a trade-off. I mentioned that you want to do a linear projection from N to N, right? From M, where did I put it?
germayne: You want to do a linear projection from… oh, sorry.
germayne: You want to do a linear projection from N to N. N is your original dimension. If I'm keeping the original dimension, I might as well don't do linear transformation, right?
germayne: Of course, I get to choose… I get to choose between
germayne: Right? I get to choose between… let's say if I have 10 original dimension, I get to choose M to be between 1,
germayne: and 10. You get to choose it. Of course, if you choose maximum reduction, that depends on how much each of the components can explain the data, right? And if you choose back to the original dimension, then you might as well don't do the transformation to reduce the dimension.
germayne: Okay, so you can see here, that is a parameter to tweak.
germayne: And it depends on all dataset. You need to try it out.
germayne: Okay, generally speaking.
germayne: Okay, so, one last thing for PCA that's super important, because PCA is trying to make a linear combination using all your features. The idea here is that you need to scale them.
germayne: Right? So you guys start to see a very common pattern about feature scaling, right? You need to start to scale your features. And the reason for that is you do not want some features to dominate the others, right? Because you are doing some kind of linear transformation. So make sure that before you do PCA, you scale your data first.
germayne: Okay, so that's the takeaway. And we will show in the notebook later on that you get to choose the N, right? Mathematically, each of the components actually have some kind of width to it, right? Mathematically, I'm not going to go into details, but there's actually some kind of eigen
germayne: value, right? If you guys know what eigenvalue is, oh, sorry. So, essentially, there's some kind of eigenvalue where each of the components is actually stacked ranked by this eigenvalue, right? It is automatically sorted
germayne: By the highest value to the lowest, the highest to the lowest.
germayne: Okay? And normally what you want is you always want to retain the higher… the higher value, and drop off the one with the lowest value. Because the idea is the one with the largest value, the one with the largest variance, actually contains the information
germayne: that encodes the entire original feature space. So you'll want to choose
germayne: usually the first component up to, like, certain components, right? You'll choose this, and you'll throw away the rest. Because the idea is that this X number of data, this M number of dimension, captures enough information such that I do not need the original M dimension.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And one thing usually when you start to do PCAs, you want to do this diagnostic, right, which is called the explained cumulative variance. So if you imagine, right, imagine my data… so usually, if you look at this graph, I only give part of a graph up to n component. Imagine I have 300 original features, I have 3… my data set is
germayne: A dimension of 300 columns.
germayne: And the cumulative variance will actually go all the way to 1, right? Which is the maximum variance. I want to ask you guys, do you guys think it's expected?
germayne: So basically, what I'm saying is that if your original dimension is, N, I'm going to draw here, if your original dimension is N, and let's say n is equal to 300.
germayne: What I'm telling you guys is that if I plot this graph all the way up to 300 components, it will just go all the way to 1, which is the maximum variance explained for the dataset.
germayne: Is that intuitive?
germayne: That's intuitive, right? Because if I'm keeping your original space, I will have the whole data to explain. There's no loss of information.
germayne: So what you want is that if you do the explained variance curve, you should be able to see that actually the top, the top number of components usually has the strongest number of explained variants. You can basically see, right, at this point, right, up to 20 components can really explain almost 70, 75% of the variance of the data.
germayne: Right? And if you see, right, if I choose up to 80, from 20 to 80, I can only increase my explained variance from 0.75 to 0.9. So you basically can see that it's like a diminishing curve, right?
germayne: The idea is that the lower components actually has less of an importance, right? So, the trade-off here is you play around.
germayne: Should I drop off certain information at the expense of losing some stuff in order to capture some of the information, or should I not?
germayne: And you can basically see that these explained variants
germayne: the cumulative variance, actually, mathematically, it computes using the eigenvalue. Not important for you guys, but the fact is that this curve can actually tell you whether the projection works or not. If
germayne: the number of components required to explain the full percentage of data is required to be very high. It means that this transformation actually did not work. But in this case, you can see that the transformation worked perfectly. In the hypothetical case of 300 components.
germayne: I can just take 60 of them, and it almost explains 90% of the variance. It's able to explain 90% of the spread.
germayne: Right? That means that the remaining 240 dataset is actually useless. I don't really need that dimension. I don't need… I don't need it to be that high.
germayne: Okay? Now, the homework for you guys is that
germayne: In the course, people usually teach this, but if your question to me is, does this always work? What do you think? The answer is going to be, it depends, I don't know. It depends, okay? So please try it out in your Kaggle dataset, and hopefully you guys can find out the answer and let me know.
germayne: Okay, so I'm going to… I'm going to move off a bit, we're not going to… we're not going to do too much about this exercise, okay? These are all optional, but I'm just going to give a bit of explanation about manifold. So normally, if you go into a curriculum, people will talk about, oh, okay, you know, I mentioned that… I mentioned that PCA is a linear transformation, but you know that sometimes data is not linear, right?
germayne: sometimes data is nonlinear. So what I want to do is, I just want… I want to spend just a bit of time talking about the motivation of nonlinear, right? So the idea for nonlinear, usually you can see this as manifold learning, it's basically just a nonlinear version of
germayne: of transforming the data from a high-dimensional space to a lower-dimensional space. I'll provide some link.
germayne: If you're interested, you can read up, right? This is a perfect good
germayne: material for you to read more about Manifold, but for the… for the purpose of this course, I don't think we are really going very deep.
germayne: But the idea here is that you just want to find some kind of transformation where you want to understand the underlying meaning of the data, right? So the idea here is that if, let's say, the, you know, we all live in a three-dimensional space, right?
germayne: Imagine a tissue paper. A tissue paper is two-dimensional. When a tissue paper is flat, it's two-dimensional.
germayne: This two-dimensional tissue paper
germayne: the innate representation of the tissue paper is two-dimensional, right? But we live in a three-dimensional space. Imagine if I crush the paper. I crush the tissue paper. The tissue paper becomes a ball, right? The ball is actually now three-dimensional.
germayne: But the underlying information about the tissue paper is two-dimensional. So what you want is, you want to find some kind of transformation to transform and unwrap the crushed tissue paper from three-dimensional back to two-dimensional. So the idea is that the innate representation of the information is actually two-dimensional.
germayne: Even though in three-dimensional, even though the transformation to the paper is in three-dimensional. And many times for your dataset, they can be in high-dimensional.
germayne: But maybe the underlying information is actually lower dimensional. So you want to find some kind of transformation, and manifold learning actually expands this by going to a lot of nonlinear transformation. Of course, we don't have time to talk about it.
germayne: Right, so I'll leave this for those of you who are interested.
germayne: And some intuition here is that you can see some examples. This halo, this generated hello data is from the same link. This halo is actually generated in a two-dimensional space. You can see this is two-dimensional, right? The halo.
germayne: we apply some kind of transformation to the halo to make it three-dimensional, so you can see this is three-dimensional. So this halo is now transformed into three-dimensional. But the original structure of the data is actually
germayne: two-dimensional, right? And when you apply some kind of linear projection, this is another kind of linear projection, right? Not PCA, we do something called MDS, right? And apparently, because the data now is nonlinear, the relationship is nonlinear.
germayne: it is not able to revert it back to the halo. Essentially, it becomes an S, you can see, right? So what this means is that…
germayne: sometimes the transformation might not work. You might not…
germayne: unwrap the data into the original representation, and from a very abstract perspective, you will never ever know what is the true representation of the data, right? You will not see it. But from an abstract perspective, the idea is you want to find this transformation that really best describes and maintains the relationship of your data.
germayne: Okay, so this is out of, out of, out of topic. So, actually, there's also another type of, transformation, it's called TISNI. It is quite popular for visualization.
germayne: Okay, I will show some examples, but I really won't go too deep.
germayne: But there are some math that, if you are interested, you can see in the notebook, right? Essentially, it does KL divergence, right? And the idea here is that imagine you have some kind of relationship of the data in very big dimension, right? What you want to do is you want to retain as much as possible the relationship.
germayne: Back to the lower dimension, while maintaining the
germayne: relationship, and we use it using some kind of probability, and we are using KL divergence to minimize the difference. Again, not very important, but the idea here is that TISNI is actually used very common for visualizing, right? It's able to
germayne: you know, transform the data nonlinearly from a very high dimension to a low dimension, right? But the problem here is that, right, you guys learned that, you know, when lower dimension, we always think about distances, right, correct? When we think about K and N, you guys always think, like, oh, okay, if the dot,
germayne: if the… if the… if the dot, right? If the dot… I always think about, you know, this dot and this dot is actually near because of some kind of distance, right? You learn that there's things like Euclidean distance, blah blah blah, right? There's some kind of distance metric.
germayne: But the problem is that Tisney doesn't preserve distance, right? Visually, it might look very near, but it does not preserve distance.
germayne: Okay? So please be careful.
germayne: Which is why we're not going to go very deep.
germayne: Okay? I'm going to give you guys a link, you guys can play out, fantastic.
germayne: fantastic, link to play around. You can play around each of the parameters and see how each of the data is transformed, right? You can basically play around with the perplexity, the dimension, the epsilon, to see how does the data transform, okay? But we won't be covering this.
germayne: Okay? So please be careful. The takeaway for TISNE is that we be very, very, very careful. A lot of people say that, oh, you know, after I do TISNE, I can just do clustering. But the problem is that a lot of clustering algorithms, later on, you see, unsupervised learning, they like to talk about distance, right? They like to think about, oh.
germayne: nearest distance is actually similar, but Tisney doesn't preserve distance, so please be careful.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: All good, right? Okay, so the takeaway from here, before I go too soon, is you have unlocked PCA for your Kaggle.
germayne: Okay, so please try out, see whether it works.
germayne: Okay, so, anybody, any last questions?
germayne: If not, I will hand over to Soon.
germayne: To do the notebook, and then we will come back later to finish up.
germayne: Unsupervised learning.
germayne: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Thank you, Jamie.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Let me share my screen.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so here's a notebook for the Module 3.5.
Soon | NTU: So… Please go to the outline.
Soon | NTU: in the… Explorer.
Soon | NTU: Right, please go to this outline, and then go to dimensionality reduction.
Soon | NTU: Okay, to locate the section which we're going to cover first, right, because we have already skipped the first section on anomaly detection and outliers, right? So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have…
Soon | NTU: Already gone through some of the detail of dimensionality reduction, and knowing that this technique is very useful.
Soon | NTU: to help us to reduce the number of dimensions that we have in the dataset, right? Mainly to
Soon | NTU: Okay, to me, it's more for visualization, right? Okay. So, we are going to use this
Soon | NTU: Irish dataset. Okay, so this data set, I think, is a very appropriate dataset to elaborate the concept of
Soon | NTU: a dimensionality reduction, okay? The reason is… It has 4 columns.
Soon | NTU: of sapir and also the pedal length and width, okay? Plus one label column, so a total of 5. Now, if you have 4 feature columns, right, so that means, if you want to visualize this.
Soon | NTU: Each of this row or data point on your
Soon | NTU: scatter plot or chart, you know, it is not possible, right? You can't plot a data point in a 4D4 dimension, okay? So let's look at the data set.
Soon | NTU: into a data frame, right? So this is the… Okay, let me…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you need to run the…
Soon | NTU: the import statement to import the SNS, the CBON library, right? Otherwise, you will have some error.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's, run this.
Soon | NTU: So, we have only about 150 rows, a very small data set, with 4-column, numeric column.
Soon | NTU: So, for this PCA, we will not, include the labor column.
Soon | NTU: Alright, because, I think we need to use numeric data for your PCA, okay? So this is what the…
Soon | NTU: We're trying to store the numeric column name into this numeric column variable.
Soon | NTU: And then… We will… have to import the PCA class from the decomposition library of Sakit-learn.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So we just, remember that you… Have, chosen to… run the, kernel in the ML.
Soon | NTU: Otherwise, you have a lot of errors, okay? So now, it is
Soon | NTU: very, useful to know what this PCA class can do, especially those parameters that you can set, right? Some of them are, you know, you can set it for maybe
Soon | NTU: visualization purpose. In sum, you may have to specify, oh, because of the choice of your algorithm, your S…
Soon | NTU: VD, single value decomposition algorithm, and also the other parameters. Okay, so you can use Question mark, PCA?
Soon | NTU: And then, you will have a lot of information
Soon | NTU: Right? You can find in this cell. But of course, for a more detailed documentation of the PCA class, it's always advisable to go to the Scikit-learn official website, right? So usually, what I would do is,
Soon | NTU: I go to the website and say.
Soon | NTU: you say, right, search for this sklearn, right? So I believe by now you should be very familiar with this, how to access to this, sklearn, right? To show you a… just a quick…
Soon | NTU: Alright, so this is how we get all this, information, right?
Soon | NTU: So I will not go through the detail, but just to tell you how to get this info, so that you know how to
Soon | NTU: Get the information in the future for your reference.
Soon | NTU: So now, next, we are going to create a PCA object with a component of
Soon | NTU: Sorry, your, your code is…
Soon | NTU: number of components is 2, right? Okay, so just now I'm trying to play with it by setting it to 4. So, let's create a PCA,
Soon | NTU: Because we want to visualize the result in a scatter plot, so that's why we only are interested in getting the two most, so-called the components from the IRIS dataset, okay? So these two components.
Soon | NTU: will have the most, variance, okay, to explain the most variance in your data set, as we will see later, right? So, and then we will feed the PCA
Soon | NTU: Data.
Soon | NTU: with the Iris, The four numeric column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so basically what we have done is…
Soon | NTU: we make PCA now familiar with the number inside the IRIS dataset, and then We will prenote.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this indeed is an object with two components.
Soon | NTU: Right, but…
Soon | NTU: the component is still unknown, we still do not know what it is, okay, so we shall see later. Now, this statement is to do the actual, computation to find out the eigenvalue, eigenvector, okay? So, to tell PCA, position
Soon | NTU: You know, the… that, that line, yeah, just now, Jermaine has, shared with you.
Soon | NTU: that line, so that all the data point, 150 data points, when it projected onto this line, okay, has the maximum variation, okay? What do I mean by that? When you say maximum variation means you should not have
Soon | NTU: A lot of overlap between data points.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so these data points should be further away from each other, so you have to adjust the line so that the variance is the max.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is what the, transform statement is doing.
Soon | NTU: And then, let's block… it visually.
Soon | NTU: on the scatter plot, and you can see there are actually 3 distinctive clusters, right, formed by using this PCA.
Soon | NTU: Right? But the vertical and the horizontal axis are not labeled with the length and the width of the pedal, or…
Soon | NTU: because PCA are not a direct so-called mapping of the original fiscal measurement, right? So…
Soon | NTU: You just have to have a vertical and horizontal axis like this, okay? And then with the label, the cluster.
Soon | NTU: With a color like this.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So, in this manner, we can actually use the PCA to help to reduce the number of dimensions in the IRIS dataset from 4
Soon | NTU: 2, 2.
Soon | NTU: Okay? But of course, you can also… Huck-coded to use.
Soon | NTU: you know, the zipper length and the pedal width, and so on, to plot your chart, okay? But that will not mean
Soon | NTU: I would say you are basically not getting the full picture of what this clustering is showing you.
Soon | NTU: Okay, comparing with using the PCA method.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So the tool is, depending on the number of variables that you want to
Low Keng Teck, Noel: bleh, that means the number of X, the number of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: X are the features, that you want to play with,
Soon | NTU: Okay, the choice of these components, right, usually we will not put it as number of components 4 lah, right? Because you cannot plot it on the… on the… on the chart, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So I'm thinking, I'm thinking, like, you know, like, because in the model, right, you can… the X and the Y, they both play a part.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So when you have, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: X and… no, you have put 2, for example. Are you assuming that one of them is X and the other one is Y, or are you assuming that 2 is X, or… or what? You know what I'm thinking?
Soon | NTU: For clustering algorithm, right, we usually do not have this Y, which we call the label column, right? We let the algorithm, you know, find a pattern for us.
Soon | NTU: we, we won't take and say, oh, you know… of course, we, we have to have, specify the hyperparameter, okay? So, in this case,
Soon | NTU: Number of casters, Okay, but…
Soon | NTU: That's what K means, but for PCA, you know that even though we have specified the number of components as 2,
Soon | NTU: Right? But… PCA is able to give you
Soon | NTU: Clustering like this, okay? Because based on your species, right, Right? With two components.
Soon | NTU: to explain all the variation in your data, okay? So we still do not know whether these variations in your data set is
Soon | NTU: good enough. Good enough means as close to 100% as possible, so that your error, you know, your…
Soon | NTU: Yo, yo… your error in your clustering is as low as possible, okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So.
Soon | NTU: So… no.
Soon | NTU: even though I use these fishes to color the dots, okay, but I'm not using it to tell the PCA
Soon | NTU: Algorithm to… Find a pattern for me.
Soon | NTU: I only do it after, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so as you can see, if I put back the species column, right, which is the…
Soon | NTU: the respective ivory species. So we can see, oh.
Soon | NTU: you can actually tell there are actually 3 distinctive groups. Of course, there's some overlap here, but I think that is good enough to give us some kind of a clue as to the kind of species
Soon | NTU: But we already know there are three species, okay? So it's like preachit lah, okay? But if you applied it to the real
Soon | NTU: let's say, well, data set. You may be having a dataset of, from your marketing, let's say your department. A colleague give you, you know, a few
Soon | NTU: 100,000 and try to…
Soon | NTU: tell you, can you do some clustering? And then, making use of PCA, you can visualize there's actually some pattern in your data.
Soon | NTU: So this is what you can make use of, you know, to visualize your result.
Soon | NTU: Using the PCA techniques.
Teng Lee LIM: Hi, soon.
Soon | NTU: Yes, technically.
Teng Lee LIM: So, from this table, right, that you are saying, so am I right to say that, based on the two components.
Teng Lee LIM: If we didn't color the species, we can only tell that probably there's two.
Teng Lee LIM: to group there. Am I right to say that?
Teng Lee LIM: Because VC is in the… it has something like the Y value, right?
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes. So, mathematically, you can tell, if I don't color the groups, the data points right, you can just say, visually, there are two groups.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Good thing.
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you.
Soon | NTU: But it so happened that, we are…
Soon | NTU: plain cheat lah, okay? We are using labor data set.
Soon | NTU: supposed to be for supervised learning. We use it for unsupervised learning.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so in this case, it's to do, clustering, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: not a very good example, okay? But nevertheless, we can still see that, based on our information, which I can still owe.
Soon | NTU: Even with two… dimension, PCA1 and PCA2, we can see some distinct pattern in your data.
Soon | NTU: Meaning? Oh…
Gwen Lim: Sorry, sir, please stop me.
Soon | NTU: Yes?
Gwen Lim: Oh, I was wondering, so, you know,
Gwen Lim: Because, we're asking also for, if it's not colored, right? There's two groups. Is there also a way of creating artificial clusters in order to do a back propagation method for a different form of training? Say if they wanted to have a very specific model?
Soon | NTU: Using back propagation.
Gwen Lim: Yes, so, like, so instead of those two groups, right, say in the middle, if there's a gap.
Gwen Lim: And then they know there's actually 4 species instead of just 3.
Gwen Lim: Can they… are people, do you… have you… is there a technique to put in?
Gwen Lim: Artificial clusters, just to see whether the fourth group exists or not.
Gwen Lim: Or to train the model to take a look and see whether there's a missing… there's missing information.
Gwen Lim: So, like, say, like, yeah, so over there, right, there's an empty spot, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Gwen Lim: Oh, the roomies.
Soon | NTU: the amount of information that is missing, right, we can actually take a look at the, the PCA, okay, because inside this PCA, variable, right, it contains a lot of,
Soon | NTU: With a lot of, the eigenvalue, vector, and so on, okay? Which,
Soon | NTU: We'll take a look at it later.
Soon | NTU: Right? I'll show you how we can…
Gwen Lim: Thank you.
Soon | NTU: use the PCA to give you more information as to, hey, we only have two components, reduce it from four.
Soon | NTU: from 4 features to 2, okay? So how much data we have… how much information we have lost in the
Soon | NTU: transformation process from 4D to 2D, okay? So this is something you can get from some, web
Soon | NTU: the, PCA variable.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: I will show you later, because I think there is, right here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me see…
Soon | NTU: I will bypass the Disney section, right, just to save more time for, us to cover more.
Soon | NTU: theory on the, other clustering algorithm. Okay, let me go to… the bottom…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have… okay, so this is actually the next section. Okay, let me see…
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me see. Okay, let me, let me give myself a…
Gwen Lim: I don't need to skip if, if.
Soon | NTU: Give myself a challenge.
Gwen Lim: Cool, yeah, it looks cool.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now I have Vic here…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let me see what I can do.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Show the, x-pin variations…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now, this explained variance ratio, okay, so is to show you, out of these 4 originally, okay, if I used 4 features, I would have 100%
Soon | NTU: Variance. Total variance, explained, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, now, if I only choose 2,
Soon | NTU: Okay, now you can see 92 means… 0.92 means 92%. So the PCA1 is already able to explain to you the 92% of your variance in your iris dataset. So the remaining is 0.055%, so a total of 0.5%.
Soon | NTU: 97… so only… the Knicks…
Soon | NTU: Third and the fourth feature, which we have not included, only explain the remaining 3%. So, a loss of 3% out of
Soon | NTU: you only retain 97. Is it good enough for you?
Soon | NTU: So that should be very good, right? Okay. So in this way, you can actually tell, oh, having a PC8 1 and 2 is good enough.
Soon | NTU: You know, I do not want to include two more dimensions because I cannot visualize my results.
Soon | NTU: Right? So that is the, maybe the purpose of the, the PCA, to help you. One of the use cases of the PCA is to help you to visualize your results.
Soon | NTU: And yet, you do not do it at the expense of losing so much of your variants in your dataset.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: So, if you want to put it as
Soon | NTU: Four, you, you can do it yourself.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you can see this is a total 100% I was mentioning, if you include everything. So if the third feature only explains about 1.7,
Soon | NTU: Right, percent, and this one is 0.5. So, that's pretty…
Soon | NTU: There's only to retain it as a standalone feature for your
Soon | NTU: When you do your, whatever, data analytics, huh?
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that wraps up the first part of the Jupyter Notebook.
Soon | NTU: Right, any other questions from anyone? I hope this explained variance ratio is, very clear. Of course, you can also ex…
Soon | NTU: Please show… the weeds.
Soon | NTU: the original… Okay, so he can also…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this PCA… well, now, PCA is actually a…
Soon | NTU: Linear transformation of your original feature into some so-called,
Soon | NTU: into the respective component that we have specified, okay? So these are the weights.
Soon | NTU: of the original component in your IVIS dataset. Okay, so if you look at this, right, This is actually…
Soon | NTU: PC com… PCA1, right, this 0.92 is actually make use of this 0.36 times your… this…
Soon | NTU: plus negative this, times this, and so on. Okay, so different components have a different, formula, but I would say
Soon | NTU: This one have a more…
Soon | NTU: able to explain your variations based on these weights in your PCA component 1 and 2.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is what you can…
Soon | NTU: take a look in more detail what the PCA variable contains after you have, transformed it using your data.
Soon | NTU: Right? Okay, so I think I, I…
Soon | NTU: I will stop here if there's no more questions.
Soon | NTU: If you have an additional question and…
Soon | NTU: you, you can post it in the Discord. Okay, I can see a lot of,
Soon | NTU: Okay, let's have a 10-minute break, starting from now.
Soon | NTU: Okay, good.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But I noticed that we didn't say what the component is,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So that means we have to, like… I mean, Kayla, maybe this is the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: From the supervised training one, but…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But if, let's say, it's an unsupervised one, then… then we do not know what the component is, right? Although we know that this component one is very good.
Soon | NTU: You only know that PCA1 is, is…
Soon | NTU: Related to the original fiscal, so-called column.
Soon | NTU: The original feature, okay, in this manner.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So you're saying that column 1 here with… component 1 here refers to the column 1 in the… when we first have the table?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Or the 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, the one… that component one refers to the row number…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Number one. Like, row zero, is it? Column, row, row 0.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is that how I look at it? I mean, like, this component one down here.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's actually the… in the… because we have data… we have a data frame rate for the Iris.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, the component here… So I try to identify component 1 first to which role is it?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Or is it, I don't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: How shall I read this? I just don't understand.
Soon | NTU: Which role, or what?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, like, I tried to identify this, principal component one, right? It refers to which… which… which flower, I mean, like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it Santosa, or is it Vechunica, or what? I don't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: We won't know lah, right?
Soon | NTU: AIF, you will know. Of course, you can always, join back with…
Soon | NTU: The original data set to plot and compare it with the respective So-called, custard…
Soon | NTU: ID, okay, compared with the actual ground crew.
Soon | NTU: And you'll see, oh, whether this kind of, PCA technique really is useful.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, okay. But we will do it not using PCA, but we will do it using, k-means later, so we'll go through it, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, because I was trying to… I thought from here, we would know, like, what… which component you're talking about, you know, like, but it seems like we… we still will not know. We just know that one component is very good, and, you know, another one is also good, but we actually do not know… at this point in time, we still do not know which is good, which is… which… which component is it, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Correct.
Soon | NTU: I already said Component 1 and 2 are good.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, but we don't want Comporo 1 East, mah.
Soon | NTU: Component one is a combination of this… by this rate.
Teng Lee LIM: Component 1 is not a feature, right?
Soon | NTU: is.
Teng Lee LIM: Combination… it's a…
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, young.
Soon | NTU: It's a resolve feature.
Teng Lee LIM: It's a combination of co-.
Soon | NTU: Our important point.
Teng Lee LIM: I'll get it.
Soon | NTU: A feature that you have transformed, you know, Using the PCA techniques.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so in the end, we will not know which component… at this point in time, like, we don't know what it is, like, which feature it is, right, or which combination of feature it is, right?
Teng Lee LIM: It uses all Noel, if you look at the result. The length, the width, the length, the width.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But we don't know which flower is it, what?
Teng Lee LIM: I thought you would just order flour.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Because a PCA is not for you to predict. It's for timing.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean, I'm not talking about prediction, but I'm talking about, like, you know, if you say that, well, this, this land and this view, that means it must equal to some flower lah, or… No, no, no. Or even if it's, like, all the flower, then.
germayne: Let me…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: If it's not, then…
Soon | NTU: do that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: la.
Soon | NTU: Can you come to that, the prediction versus the ground truth in k-means.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, that means there's another step we do before we know which…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Which feature, or which flower is it, right?
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes, okay, so when we come to K-Mins, we will have more, maybe, clarity provided.
germayne: Can I, can I, can I talk? Can I explain?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Sorry.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Don't apologize. I'm just saying, can I just say something? So, I think pertaining to your question, right? Can you hear me, right? I'm audiobook.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I can hear you, I can hear you.
germayne: Okay, so just to clarify, the mapping to the flowers still exists. So in the Iris data, each row
germayne: I cannot remember how much is, or how many. Okay, so in this… in this story data set, there's 4 features, right?
germayne: Definitely.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: flowers, I know.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Chief Hollywood.
germayne: So, it fall features, 3 flowers, yeah?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, yeah.
germayne: So, essentially, you think of your data, there's four columns, and there is a target label. If you do PCA on your X, right, which is the… the… the four… these four different description
germayne: of the… each of the flowers, you basically resulted in some components. Each component still has a mapping to the flower type. What you lose, however, is the original feature, because every component now becomes a combination of all the features.
germayne: And by definition, each component are ordered
germayne: with their importance in terms of the maximal variance. The first component will have the largest.
germayne: And diminishes all the way to the… original N dimensions component.
germayne: Right? So, obviously, what we are again saying is that when you choose one component, it is a linear combination. Linear combination means that it's a linear sum with each of the different weights.
germayne: And it's done it in a way where the characteristic of this component is the one that maximizes the variance. It spreads the data out to the maximal. That's what it means.
germayne: Of course, interpretation, in this case, you can tell, you cannot interpret, right? Like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, my God.
germayne: So the purpose, obviously, is not to use it so that you can interpret. You are using it
germayne: From a predictive standpoint, if you want to use it to reduce away your dimension, which is what has been mentioned as the curse of dimensionality from a motivational standpoint.
germayne: You might have some features that have noise.
germayne: this can be one way to do feature selection, in a sense of, like, can I maybe use this to drop away
germayne: Information that is redundant.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, which is where I'm… where my direction is, because… so my… so… so I'm thinking that at this point in time, I do not know, but subsequent steps, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: because I was going through the whole thing, like, there are a lot of steps lah, so maybe some soon steps I would know lah. I mean, now I do not know, but, you know, it's work in progress, but the final results, I will need to know lah, so that I know what to drop or what to take, right? Yeah, that's where I'm coming from.
germayne: So what to… what to choose? That one is a… is a… is a… is a knob that you need to tweak.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, correct.
germayne: Right? So I'm sure in your group… Noel, what group are you, again? Can you tell me?
germayne: Yeah, Group 2, okay, yeah, you're doing, you're doing well. Okay, so Group 2, from Group 2 perspective, you start to realize that there's no clear answer, right? It depends on what kind of features you have. I do not know what kind of things you guys introduced.
germayne: So, it will be interesting if you try it out, and you will know.
germayne: Okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Okay, yep, yep, but good, good, good question, and, and…
germayne: Yeah, so hopefully you guys try it out, okay? It may or may not work. So nobody here is saying that, oh, you know, definitely that I've seen cases that it works, I've seen cases where it does not work.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And we are teaching here from a predictive standpoint. We are using this to predict.
germayne: And one idea is to use it as prediction, or another idea is to do it as visualization. The notebook shows visualization.
germayne: The homework for you guys is to see whether it works for prediction, okay?
germayne: Make sense?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, that's where I come from. Okay, thank you.
germayne: Welcome, welcome.
germayne: Okay, take… take some break if needed. More intense part two. Part 2 is… part… part two will be more intense.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right there.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think in one minute's time, we will start. Okay, so I think you guys realize that we skip out some stuff as optional. So in your notebook, you realize that there are some topics we didn't cover. Those are optional exercises.
germayne: These are prioritized as the most important concepts.
germayne: Okay, so if you have limited constraint, whatever that is covered today, I must know. Everything else will be optional.
germayne: All right?
germayne: So this will help you focus on what is important.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so for today, right, for…
germayne: clustering, which is the start of unsupervised learning, we will be going through three algorithms today. Okay, so we will have the whole 2 hours to talk about three algorithms.
germayne: Okay? So I want to repeat again, I want to repeat the context. Okay, sorry, before, maybe before I start, anybody got any last questions for PCA or not?
germayne: Since we have, we have ample of time today, anybody who has any last questions for PCA?
Teng Lee LIM: Yes, I have a question.
germayne: Yes, go ahead, go ahead.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, best PCA is supposed to reduce dimension.
germayne: Yep.
Teng Lee LIM: And, ish.
Teng Lee LIM: Fisher is a dimension, am I right to say that?
germayne: Yes, each feature is a dimension.
Teng Lee LIM: So that's why there's 4 features in the, 4 dimensions in the example given, right?
germayne: Hmm.
Teng Lee LIM: Then why is it after… the… going through the PCA, my component ones still have 4 dimensions.
Teng Lee LIM: Because there's four components there.
Teng Lee LIM: But with different weights.
germayne: No, no, okay, so if you, if you look at my screen, right.
germayne: the… the components are already compressed, really. So basically, right, you have, mathematically, you have like that, right, this is N.
germayne: you already mapped them to RM.
germayne: So basically, right, in your case for the iris, right, N is equals to 4.
germayne: Correct? Let's say I chose M to be… to be 2. So basically, this one is the one that you set in your… in your N components, right, in the library. So what happens… what happens is that in your feature, right.
germayne: you should now see that there should only be 3 columns. Sorry, 2 columns. Component 1 and Component 2.
germayne: Does that… does that make sense? So, this… this first row of the component, right, is already a compressed version of the original four features.
germayne: But you… you now exist only two columns, you can see, right? So let's say if I have, I don't know, I can't remember how many rows of data set you have, like, this is the number of instance, we call it number of instance. Your instance got 100, but now your dimension is only 2. Can you see? Component 1 and component 2. So my matrix now is 100 by 2, right?
germayne: Your original matrix is 100x4.
Teng Lee LIM: So… Am I?
germayne: The matrix is smaller already.
Teng Lee LIM: At this part, I understand, but… so you're saying, initially, the core feature is, like, separately?
germayne: Yes, yes.
Teng Lee LIM: Exactly. I combine the four features into form into one component, and into two components, lah.
Teng Lee LIM: Using different way. Or compressing.
germayne: Correct, correct, correct, correct, you're right, yes, correct, that's the takeaway. So each component is a linear combination of the original four features, but they compress it differently.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, okay.
germayne: Right? And, and, and, right.
germayne: Okay, so… Thank you. Yeah, so in some sense, you can see your matrix is much smaller. You, you reduce lah. You reduce by 2.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, hey, thank you.
germayne: Welcome. Tengli, you're a good one, sorry if I'm asking everybody this, I'm trying to get a sense of who is in which group.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay. Group 1.
germayne: Okay, good one, you guys still got chance, still got time, don't worry.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, or anybody else has any more questions?
germayne: Can I move on? Ready? Ready for the next one?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so we'll be going through unsupervised learning. So, clustering is actually another synonym for… for… for unsupervised learning. So, just to really cover again, so in supervised learning.
germayne: you're always trying to find a function, f of x. X is your input feature.
germayne: You want to map them to Y hat in order to predict Y, alright? That's supervised learning. In order to predict Y hat, you need to have a target label of Y. So essentially, I'm always trying to map this function, right? This function, from an abstract perspective, is just a way to predict. It's like, essentially, you can think of it like a black box.
germayne: Now, what encompasses F of X? Essentially, if you learn linear regression, it's your linear model, your coefficients. If you learn decision tree, it's basically your tree. If you do K and N, it's basically all your X data, right? So on and so forth, right? So, today, we are not… no longer doing F of X.
germayne: map to Y. Today, what we are doing is given X… oops, sorry, my X is very big. Given X, what I want to do is I want to find a partition.
germayne: Where I can partition each of the X. Basically, how can I group each of the X data together, right? So this, okay, just to be clear, I just draw a D at the bottom. So this is partition of X. What this means is that I aim to find a way to group all each of these X data into some kind of meaningful clusters, right?
germayne: You will see later on that a very big key challenge of unsupervised learning is that no matter what kind of method that's introduced today.
germayne: You… there is no way to tell you
germayne: What each of the partitions represents.
germayne: Okay, and that is the feature, not a bug.
germayne: The feature here is that, mathematically, you can find some kind of partition. Every partition has different methodology. But you will see that it's very challenging to choose what algorithm to create what kind of partition. And it is up to you to determine using different methods. Either you look at your EDA again and see what does the partition tells you to figure out
germayne: what actually the partition worked, right? If the partition worked or not.
germayne: Okay? And we'll be introducing 3 different algorithms
germayne: Right, and you will see that
germayne: it will come up with different partitions, depending on your data type. And of course, it has some key assumptions. And these are the three most common algorithms that we will go through today.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So you can see that there's actually, a few different algo. We are not going through all of them, right? We are only going to go through K-mins.
germayne: Very standard algorithm.
germayne: We'll go through k-means, we'll go through, all the hierarchical clustering, Right?
germayne: And we'll go through the density-based clustering. And these three is one of the most common clustering algorithm.
germayne: Okay? So the idea you can see is that the colors are basically the partition, right? You can see that
germayne: These algos inherently have some kind of… Assumption about the data.
germayne: And, of course, if your data is in higher dimension, you do not know what kind of assumptions if the data follows. So the only way is to think about, once you get the partition.
germayne: do some kind of EDA to understand
germayne: how, you know, what does the partition actually mean, right? If your goal is to use it as an analysis.
germayne: then it will be up to you to figure out what each of the partitions represents, and this is the problem and challenge with
germayne: clustering, right? They will introduce many different mechanisms, quantitatively, for you to measure what is good, but what is good from a structural standpoint is actually very different from your perspective, from a business standpoint, what is actually meaningful, right? And that is the challenge with
germayne: unsupervised learning.
germayne: Okay, so you can see that we don't really need any label, and different algorithms
germayne: need some kind of knock from you, right? And again, when I say knock, right? It's a bit like how you do… how you play with your supervised learning, right? As an end user, you have to make certain key decisions, like, the levers for you to make. And when you take the lever, you get very different results. You guys start to realize, right.
germayne: Correct? Can I check, huh?
germayne: I mean, in the people that submitted Kaggle, everybody tried, right?
germayne: Not just one person for everyone, right?
germayne: I hope everybody tried. So everybody knows what I mean, right, when you tweak.
germayne: Your results will be very different.
germayne: Does anybody know what I mean?
germayne: Why you guys just stare at me?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so we're going to talk about the first, the first algorithm.
Wai Kay: Oh, my children!
germayne: Okay, we'll talk about the first.
germayne: The first basic algorithm is actually called k-means clustering, right? It's a centroid-based clustering algorithm, and what it does is that the K basically just means that the number of clusters that you can choose.
germayne: So, if you can choose any clustering… So, essentially, you can see, the first challenge here is that you need to determine the number of clusters that you want to group.
germayne: That's how the algorithm works, and you will see later, I think, I believe we will share some video later.
germayne: And the algorithm is actually relatively straightforward.
germayne: But the whole idea is that you initialize with the K number of clusters, we call them the centroids, and we will iterate
germayne: And map each of the data points that you have.
germayne: into these centroids. And at the end, what you will have is you will have… you will have K distinct clusters.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, one of the… one of the idea, right, I want to give you guys this intuition that k-means clustering actually look at, is that it looks into this objective called the inertia, which is called the within-cluster sums of Square.
germayne: So the idea here is that a good cluster, okay, I want you guys to follow me, right? A good cluster is one where each cluster are very compressed.
germayne: Right? Which means the within sum of squares is actually very near. So what I want you guys to imagine is, if you have, you know, some kind of clustering data.
germayne: I'm gonna draw here. So if, let's say, you have some kind of clustering data.
germayne: A good cluster, by definition, from K-min's perspective, is that
germayne: I want the points to be very tightly together, right? Agree? So, which means that if I'm able to find two groups.
germayne: Two groups is, by definition, well separated, and very closely
germayne: Clustered together, and what they mean by that is they're going to measure that by the within sum of square.
germayne: Right, so there's going to be a centroid, which is the center point of all the data points, and I want to group them such that they are very near the center point, which means that they are very… they're grouped together very, very tightly, right? And for each cluster, they are actually very far apart from each other.
germayne: So that's actually a definition from K-means, right? K-means perspective is, that is, by definition a good cluster.
germayne: Okay? So one thing about, you know, why is dimensionality reduction also very relevant is that, if you guys remember, we have the Gaussian, for example, if you think about the Gaussian distribution.
germayne: Gaussian, even in high-dimensional spaces, you can see here, right, is that there's going to be a lot of sparsity, which means there's actually going to be a lot of gap.
germayne: If you remember the Gaussian distribution, the normal distribution, if you guys remember, is going to be a bell curve shape, right?
germayne: Which means that we expect a lot of data points to be clustered.
germayne: at some point. But this, again, is in… is in one dimension, right? We are drawing this in one dimension. But if, let's say, the Gaussian distribution in higher dimension is actually very sparse, they're actually not as cluttered together as possible. So, the whole idea is that
germayne: if you are talking about very high dimensional spaces, sometimes the data point itself might have a lot of sparsity, a lot of gaps, right? So…
germayne: Of course, if you, again, were to do PCA, right, that means, again, you lose your interpretation, right? That's the problem, right? So that is some of the key challenges here. Not saying that every time you do k-means, you need to do PCA. Sometimes you still want some kind of interpretation, you want to understand, like, oh, okay, why is this group within this cluster?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, this is essentially the algorithm. I believe we have the…
germayne: Okay, I think let's just watch for 3 minutes. Just going to open up this.
germayne: Oh, wait, let me know if you guys can hear.
germayne: Question?
germayne: What is… Kahil?
germayne: K means custom medicine.
germayne: K-means cluster analysis is one of the simplest and most common methods…
germayne: By using the k-means method, you can cluster your data by a given number of classes.
germayne: So you already need to define beforehand the number of clusters.
germayne: For example, you have a data set, and you want to cluster the traces into three clusters.
germayne: This can be done.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe you can own the subtitle.
germayne: Supplier not available. Cool.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Good question.
germayne: Okay, cannot hear, is it? Cannot hear at all. It's very loud to me, though. Cannot hear.
germayne: Can I hear you?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So far, very so far.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Feeble, feeble.
Hitesh shah: It's okay, yeah, I think it's okay.
germayne: Is it because some of you guys, the… the… can you on maybe your volume? Try try if cannot, then I'll see whether I'll play the next one. Yeah, okay, then maybe you guys just watch it, okay.
germayne: So I'll just… I'll just skip this.
germayne: Okay, so essentially, this slide, we are just going to give the intuition of how claiming clustering actually works. So you can see, if you have your data points, first, as a user, you need to define the clusters, and of course, you need to define, like, the distance metric in order to determine what is the definition of close.
germayne: And how it works is that it will first randomly create the K number of centroids, right? And what it does is that it will tries to measure, for every point, who is the nearest towards each of the centroid, and map it to it.
germayne: Right, so you can see that we have the three centroids, right, that is randomly selected. We'll then measure, for each point, the distance to the… each of the cluster.
germayne: And we will assign each point to the nearest cluster, right?
germayne: And then what we will do is, now that we have the mapping, we will then calculate the mean, right, which is the centroid, the new centroid for each of the cluster.
germayne: And from the new centroid, what we are going to do again is, we are going to recalculate for every point its distance to the new centroid, and then re-initialize the members. And once you get the member, you will recalculate the mean again, and you continue iterating until you don't get the
germayne: Change. Basically, repeat until convergence.
germayne: Okay? So, essentially, what you will have is that you will then actually see that what k-means does is that it tries to minimize the sum of square error with respect to the centroid.
germayne: Okay, so you can see it's a very relatively simple algorithm.
germayne: Okay, I want to… Ask you guys a question.
germayne: So if you guys remember, I mentioned something about K, nearest neighbor. What do you guys think in terms of processing my data I need to be aware of if I do K-mins? Anybody knows?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I need to know the…
germayne: it… What do you… what do you need to know?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: P…
germayne: So, there's something about k nearest neighbor that you need to do before you do k nearest neighbor, right?
germayne: So what must you do before Knearest neighbor, and why?
Zac Ang: the scaling…
germayne: And, okay, and do you guys think that that applies to k-means, or actually k-means is reverse to scaling?
germayne: What do you guys think, from an intuition standpoint?
Zac Ang: I think you need to scale. If not, it will be very weird.
germayne: So, Zach things need to scale. Anybody, anybody has a different take?
germayne: Need to scale or not.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I feel like no meeting.
germayne: Why? What's the intuition?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because, because we are managing distance, so I thought,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Scaling might remove the information somehow.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Unless they are, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, in linear regression, we scale because the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The things are too close, so we cannot measure… we cannot really predict that particular point.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But now we really want to maintain that distance so that we can We can,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, maintain that information.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Like, whether it should be in this group or that group.
germayne: NOL, by the way, I don't think I say that,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, okay.
germayne: conclusion, and the reason I…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's what I gathered from my reading, I'm not sure.
germayne: I don't think I talked about anything about scaling for linear regression, I don't think I mentioned that in the class.
germayne: I mean, bye.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe I was talking about, maybe I was… I don't know, I thought I read… I remember the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: scale up. Yeah, I read somewhere, I don't remember. Maybe it's a statistics all messed up, I don't sure.
germayne: okay, it's okay, good try, good try, Noel is a good try, but what… anybody else? So only, only two people. What about, what about, what about the rest? What about scaling? What's the intuition? And remember if I told you guys on Saturday that sometimes you don't need to overthink it.
germayne: Sometimes the answer is actually very obvious. Sometimes when I ask you guys something, there's no trick.
germayne: So what do you guys think? Is there, is there any…
germayne: I drink water first, while you guys give me an answer.
Teng Lee LIM: I say donate.
Teng Lee LIM: Because we are trying to group them, right? So if you were to scale them, then they will be close together, something like that.
Teng Lee LIM: they'll be, like, on the same scale, but you do one day.
Teng Lee LIM: that to happen.
germayne: Okay, so I think some of you… so, okay, so there's basically different school of thoughts here, right, so far in the group. But I want you guys to just see the intuition.
germayne: Oh, sorry, sorry, wrong one.
germayne: I got too many macho until I forgot. Yeah, here.
germayne: So again, I want to ask you guys, right, if you have two different variables, one variable, again, the scale is very, very big.
germayne: one variable, the scale is, let's say you have something like, maybe you have something like KG, and then something like, in CM.
germayne: The scale is very different. How… what do you think will affect the spread of the data?
germayne: Will the spread of data be very different? Will this affect the neighbors?
germayne: What do you guys think?
Teng Lee LIM: No.
Teng Lee LIM: Will effect, no?
germayne: I buena.
Teng Lee LIM: Because they are all spread out on the same scale, ma.
germayne: Oh, no, no, if you don't scale them, if you don't scale them, so one is in KG, one is in CM, are they in the same scale?
germayne: Or let's say this one becomes dollar, lah, I don't know.
germayne: Hypothetically, you want to group people based on their weight and how much they earn.
germayne: Will you think it'll be different?
germayne: This guy will pull them into a different… Different scale, right?
germayne: And then this guy will be very, very small.
germayne: Alright? So you can see the x-axis will pull… will pull them very far apart.
Teng Lee LIM: Yeah, but because I'm still calculating the k-min mark, so…
Teng Lee LIM: those that are apart will still be apart, and if I calculate the KMI, they will be…
Teng Lee LIM: Still be the nearest in the group together.
germayne: But then the problem is that some of the variable will actually distort how you measure what is close or not.
germayne: Correct? Because distance, in this case, is just measuring from 1.0, sorry.
germayne: It's just measuring from one point to the other, right? We're just measuring from one point to the other, let's say this distance.
germayne: We're just measuring the distance.
germayne: Correct. So actually, you can see that how you scale your data affects the distance, right? If I change the unit, the grouping changes again.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So do you… do you guys think, like, we want that?
Teng Lee LIM: No.
germayne: Yeah, so you don't want that, right? You don't want, like, the scale to actually influence how you determine close or not. So actually, it's a very, very similar idea to your K nearest neighbor.
germayne: Okay, so that should be the intuition.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so, so K means… oh, yeah, yeah, K, yeah, Zach.
Zac Ang: Sorry, I just wanted to check, does it matter what kind of scaling you use?
Zac Ang: Like, can you use standard scaling on one, and then min-max on the other, for example?
germayne: So what's your intuition?
germayne: What's your intuition here?
germayne: Maybe I'll start by…
Zac Ang: What you say, it sounds like it needs to be the same, so you should all use the same scale.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. Because if the idea here is we want to make them comparable, we should put them in the same scale, right?
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Because if we were to do standardization, they become a representation of your standard deviation, right? All of them become the same unit.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, hopefully that gives you the answer. I think you answered it yourself lah. Not me.
germayne: Okay? So, so you can see, right, k-means is actually a very, very simple algorithm, right? Conceptually, if you use it, very easy to explain to people. Agree, right? Very, very easy to explain. Basically, you just find
germayne: You just find groups that are near its natural centroid, right? Very, very easy to explain to people. If you implement it, not very difficult to explain to people, right? And also, it's scalable, right? There's an algorithm called minibatch K-mins. Essentially, you can scale it to millions of data points, right?
germayne: Drawback, right, I would say rather… I won't say it's an advantage, but it is very well suited for spherical clusters, which means that if your data is spherical.
germayne: wouldn't go back. If your data is spherical, you can see that k-means works well for it. You can see, in this picture, right, you notice that the data always goes around the circle. You can see,
germayne: Right? So it assumes that your data has a spherical structure.
germayne: Right? If your data, and if you look at it, right, from a human being perspective, you will see that actually the clusters are like that.
germayne: You guys can see, right, from a human being perspective, I would draw the cluster
germayne: and break them down along the line, right? But k-means cannot see that. K-means will always do it by circle. You can see,
germayne: Right? So what this means is that if your data is in n dimension, the true representation, the true group is spherical, then k means will be perfect. But then the question to me is that, oh man, how will I know? That's a challenge, you don't know.
germayne: Depending on what you want to interpret, depending on what you want to put into your dataset.
germayne: there will be a true grouping, but nobody knows what's the definition of true, right? Everybody will have different definition.
germayne: So that's actually what it means by the property, is that it's actually very well for cervical data, right? Of course, you can see that the hard part here is that the number of cluster is the hard part.
germayne: if I know what kind of clusters I want to determine beforehand, then in a sense, I kind of know what kind of grouping I want, right? Correct? So, you can see that it can be a good thing, or it can be a bad thing. And this is not a parameter. Later on in the notebook, we will show you that you can calculate an optimal number of clusters.
germayne: Right? Mathematically, by looking at the inertial, which is the… which is the within sum of square, you will see that
germayne: we can actually find a king point. I believe soon we'll talk about it in the notebook. You can find a king point later, and there are methods for us to do that. But again, right, to tell you guys.
germayne: The optimal K using all these methods doesn't necessarily mean the optimal K for your business use case.
germayne: Okay, and that's the problem, that's the challenge.
germayne: Right? And one thing to note.
germayne: I want to get… I want to ask you guys for an intuition, right? So, for K-Leans, right.
germayne: Essentially, the goal, again, is to make the cluster as tight as possible, and as far away as possible, right? So, can I get an intuition for you guys? If I increase K,
germayne: Will my inertia always
germayne: decrease. Inertial, basically, is the distance between the centroid to the points. So if my K increases.
germayne: Basically, instead of 3, I keep increasing K to be bigger and bigger.
germayne: Will my… will my distance between each of the centroids
germayne: reduce as well. What do you guys think? So I repeat again, huh?
germayne: Repeat again, wait, wait. Is that Noel, your answer?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, I didn't answer. Somebody answered.
germayne: Okay.
Zac Ang: Second.
germayne: Yeah, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Let me… let me, let me bite.
germayne: Okay, let me explain, let me explain again, for those of you who didn't get it. So here, you got 3 circles, right? So here, we got 3 circles. Essentially, here we define K to be 3, and the inertia is defined by the distance
germayne: between each of the points with respect to the center, and the idea is we want them to be as small as possible. So now I want to ask you guys this intuition, because now you can control K, right? I can choose any arbitrary K. If I increase K to be as big as possible.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Can I make sure that it's very, very… can I reduce this distance with the centroid to the point?
germayne: What's the intuition?
Lily Seah: Yes.
Teng Lee LIM: Yes.
germayne: Okay, Lili, why? Why do you say yes?
Lily Seah: Because, we are able to cater to all the nuance, I mean, the…
Lily Seah: The localized, those that are very, very near to each other.
germayne: Fantastic, fantastic. So basically, right, if you see, if the K becomes a number of points, every point becomes its own cluster, right, basically get the perfect
germayne: The perfect one, right?
germayne: So later on, you will see in the curve, I'm not going to spoil the fun, that
germayne: If you, of course, increase K, your inertia will always decrease, right? The error will always get better. But you want to find this king place, this king curve, where it has the largest decrease in inertia. But then again.
germayne: this metric does not guarantee that the clusters is correct, okay? Just a caveat.
germayne: Okay? So…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: number of k will decrease the number of inertia.
germayne: increase the number of k will decrease the within sum of square, the error between the distance for each of the points to the centroid.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, it will decrease that, which means it will… Which means that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The number of inertia will also…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: you should increase also, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The number of inertia will increase.
germayne: the aggregate.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Well, initial is a point, right? It's a, it's a point, it's a…
germayne: No, it's an error metric for each of the clusters, but if every point has its own cluster, then basically you are just zero lah, right?
germayne: If every point is your own, there's no point in taking the min.
germayne: Yeah, but what I'm just trying to illustrate here is that there's… I'm not giving you guys a free solution to say that, oh man, let's just do k-means always. The challenge is that K-means, you need to decide whether it works. Of course, it's a very simple algorithm, no harm trying it.
germayne: right, try on your data, but after you get your cluster, you are responsible to do the EDA to determine what each cluster, represents.
germayne: Its job is to just use
germayne: Certain structure has an algorithm to minimize the within sum of squares.
germayne: Right? But it does not tell you what does each cluster represents.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Oglet?
germayne: Okay, so typically, I'm going to tell you another hint. Not hint lah, but… So in practice, right, you know, when people think about feature engineering, actually, clustering, people also use it to…
germayne: to do feature engineering, also one kind of method. So you can see there's actually a lot of ways to do features, right? Why would people want to do cluster? What do you guys think is the intuition?
germayne: for your, for your, you know, why, why I want to introduce another cluster
germayne: for your features. Because maybe it might help me do some kind of grouping, right? Maybe…
germayne: Right? So, one method for unsupervised is that people also use this for feature engineering, right? Apart from just doing unsupervised.
germayne: Okay, so this is, of course, the most common one, and…
germayne: I would say, I would say if you have clustering, you can consider all of these clustering algorithms that we teach.
germayne: Okay, so of course, there's another one that's called the hierarchical. This is the second clustering, okay? I think, again, the video you guys can watch yourself.
germayne: Nope.
germayne: Okay, so what hierarchical clustering does, right, is that there is two approaches, right? The paradigm of clustering now is you can either do what is called the bottom-up, which is the algorithm narrative, or you can just do the top-down.
germayne: So basically, the paradigm is as such, right? Bottom-up basically means that I treat every individual point as its own cluster.
germayne: Right?
germayne: And I start by joining them using some kind of linkage mechanism, and eventually, If I do bottom-up.
germayne: I will start with everybody has individual cluster.
germayne: So here you can see in this example, we have 6 data points, 6 individual data points.
germayne: We will start by grouping them one by one, right? All the way until all six of them become one cluster.
germayne: Okay? So that's called bottom-up.
germayne: Top-down starts the opposite way. Top-down is…
germayne: All of them will start out as one cluster, and then we start splitting them.
germayne: Okay, of course, bottom-up is the more, more, more, more, more common one. Most people use bottom-up.
germayne: Okay? So the idea here is that
germayne: If you start bottom up, each of them will be its own
germayne: respective data point, which is its own cluster. And you can see the first merge is, I will start merging A to B,
germayne: and D to E, right? And if you look at the curve, right? Oh, actually, they look like they are the closest.
germayne: And after I merge A and B as one cluster, the next I'll merge is, because they are one cluster, right, they're no longer independent. We start by merging AB together with C, so we can see A, B,
germayne: becomes with C.
germayne: Right? And then, of course, another one that we want to start merging is DE starts to merge with F. So you can see DE starts to merge with F. At this point in time, essentially, we have
germayne: what, two clusters left. So, of course, the final step is to merge these two clusters into one cluster. And you can see the resulting dendrogram, this is basically what we call a dendrogram. Essentially, it captures… it captures the merging distances for every point, all the way from its… all the way from its leaf, all the way back to the root.
germayne: So you can remember this term that I mentioned, it's a similar name as a decision tree. The bottom is really called the leaf, the item at the top is the root.
germayne: So we basically built this dendrogram.
germayne: And the idea here is that you determine where to cut the tree, right? Where you want in terms of the number of clusters, depending on where you want to cut the tree. You can choose to cut the tree at the bottom, then you basically have, you know, if I cut here.
germayne: essentially, I'll have A and B as one cluster, C as one cluster, DE as one cluster, F as one cluster. If I cut at the top, then basically ABC is one cluster, right? DEF is one cluster. So the higher you cut, obviously, the less, the less…
germayne: Number of clusters that you have.
germayne: Right? So, from this perspective, you realize that there's still one thing that we are missing, right? Is how do we define what is the closest?
germayne: Again, right, for all these algorithms, you need to define the distance metric. How do I define the method to calculate the distance? But notice one thing, notice one thing here.
germayne: If I were to group A and B together.
germayne: How do I know what is the distance between the AB cluster to C?
germayne: F, D, E, and C, right? Because if you look at the chart here, A, why am I using B as a representation of A and B? Can you guys notice?
germayne: I could have used A, right? I could have taken the average, right? Why do I use this B? So you realize that one criteria here is actually what we call the linkage.
germayne: Right, essentially, you will see later, the linkage is the mechanism of how we define what is the nearest.
germayne: for each of D,
germayne: clustering, when we start to group them towards the top. And, fun fact, what you choose, of course, will lead to different
germayne: clustering results, right? Because the way you aggregate, the way you measure the distance is… sorry, the way you measure the closest… how do you define the closest is different for each of the linkage you will see later.
germayne: Right? So different methods, oh man, give me different clustering. Again, Does it tell you…
germayne: What does the cluster represent? It doesn't.
germayne: Right? All it does is, mathematically, you have some kind of definition to link up
germayne: How do we define the metric of the distance, as well as how do we define the nearest?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So you can see, right, resulting…
germayne: Output from a dendrogram is really this, sorry, what resulting output of a hierarchical cluster is that you get a free buffet of this dendrogram.
germayne: And where you make the decision is look at the dendrogram, and you can choose and cut.
germayne: At different height, in order to determine the number of cluster.
germayne: So… Comparing this to k-means.
germayne: You do not have to define the cluster. What you instead have is, because it's grouping, let's say, bottom up, everybody starts out as a cluster, you group all the way into one cluster, and what you want to make a decision here is to cut which part of the tree.
germayne: Right? In order to determine the clusters. So how is this actually typically used? It depends, there are many use cases. For my use case, for example, maybe I have a use case where I want to build an algorithm that I might want to start off at the bottom. So maybe I might want to pick a choice to cut at the bottom.
germayne: But then, maybe I can have some kind of business logic to say that maybe I might want to group them later on, right, in a geospatial perspective.
germayne: So there are… there are really many use cases for this, right? One use case I use personally is on the geospatial perspective. I can… I can… let's say, for example, if I think about, maybe Jurong, right? Maybe one of the clusters is Jurong East.
germayne: drawing… drawing… okay, sorry, drawing is a bad example, I'm not very good at drawing.
germayne: Let me use, like, let's say a town area, sorry, let me just use a town area.
germayne: So let's say if you… if you do some kind of geospatial cluster, right? You can imagine you can cluster them at certain geospatial locations, maybe, like, Marina, Marina Bay, you can cluster them at downtown, but then if you go up the… if you go up the dendrogram, maybe actually I'll cluster the entire south region, right? Correct?
germayne: So essentially, I can think about it from a geospatial perspective. I might have some use case where I want to group
germayne: bookings or something from a geospatial manner, and I guarantee that I'll always be grouping them at a smaller group, and I know that how they will… how they will match when they start to go up. So basically, I can group them smaller, and if I want to group the groups, I'll just basically cut the dendrogram higher, and then maybe then I'll group them in district.
germayne: So, it really depends on your use case, right? And hierarchical clustering gives you this flexibility to cut the dendrogram.
germayne: Okay, so what I mentioned here is that, you can basically see that there is actually four, popular linkage types.
germayne: the linkage type essentially determines what will the final cluster look like, because what it does is that you are defining how you actually define the distance between the cluster. You can see here.
germayne: here we are defining the nearest, here we are defining the furthest, here we are taking, like, the average, and then what, of course, is a different method, right? So essentially, each method, right, will give you different clusters.
germayne: Again, you can use other mathematical approach to determine what is the best cluster with respect to your data, but it does not guarantee that that means that it is correct.
germayne: So I don't think it's important, okay? But if you guys want to look up, there's actually something called the Copenhethic, I think, the Copenhethic correlation.
germayne: So basically, you can see which linkage type best preserves the information of your distance of the data. But then the thing is that if you do that, it does not necessarily guarantee that it's the cluster that you want, based on your business criteria, or based at what you want to interpret out of it.
germayne: So, again, it becomes, like, kind of, like, some options, and of course, it has different recommendations on what kind of results that it will become. But is it really…
germayne: you know, able to help you decide the linkage? Maybe not, right? That's why somehow it's challenging if you want to use these to interpret from a business standpoint.
germayne: Okay? But of course, you can see the good thing about this is that you don't have to define the number of clusters, that's good.
germayne: you just start by seeing which data sets actually group together, which are the ones that can be possible potential neighbor. In my use case, of course, I do it from a geospatial perspective, right? I might want to see that maybe in certain criteria, in certain booking level, in the map.
germayne: are there actually certain clusters that can be grouped first, rather than look at it from a district perspective? Right? So, hierarchical clustering, if I want to do it for that use case, I will use it, because I can cut the dendrogram.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Of course, one thing about the hierarchical clustering is the computation, and one thing, empirically, is that
germayne: Based on a lot of libraries, you actually provide what is called the distance matrix.
germayne: So essentially, the distance matrix is basically a i by j matrix, which contains every distance of the pairwise point.
germayne: So if I have i data, I number of data points, and J number of data points, I just need to provide for every data point, which is the pairwise distance. And this distance matrix will actually allow you to compute all of the clustering. So a lot of algorithms will want you to provide the distance matrix.
germayne: So this is actually pretty good, because you can pre-calculate
germayne: The input data needed to perform hierarchical clustering.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So you can see that the linkage criteria is actually, difficult lah, unfortunately. So, there's no easy way to say that, oh, you know, always do single linkage, always do complete, because each of them, depending on your data, will be different.
germayne: Alright?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Can I add something?
germayne: Sure, sure.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, my God.
germayne: I'll stop, I'll stop first, yes?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, maybe I'm confused, so I just asked.
germayne: Hmm, we'll hear.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So the, the thing is, earlier you talked about PCA, right, then where, where you… Will you…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You, you can, you can, you define, like, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because in the example, the notebook, you have,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: 3 clusters, right? You can see two each clusters.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, in hierarchical, are you saying that… although, although, you know, earlier we established, like, each cluster component is a mixture of all the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: All the different… features or whatever, all the features are mixed up.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So in… so… so this point that you met, you, you just talked about earlier, right? You know, you… we do not know where it's cut, where to cut, and, you know, or, like, we do not know where does it belong to, right? Are you saying… are you… are we talking about the same thing? The same… the same reason, that's why we cannot…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because I get this sense that, because in the end, we will need to know, like, oh, this component make this catchy from which feature, right? We need to know that.
germayne: I think I… hey, let me try my best to understand what you're asking, let me try, let me try.
germayne: Oh, wait, there's a dot in the middle.
germayne: Okay, okay. Wait, okay, I think, I think, right, there's a very easy way, okay, I'm trying my best to understand where the confusion is, okay? So, first thing is,
germayne: Just to be clear, today, right, we are talking about two different things. First, we talk about
germayne: This is feature.
germayne: transformation.
germayne: This is your unsupervised. There are two different things.
germayne: Unsupervised.
germayne: Right? PCA comes under the context of transforming your feature.
germayne: It does not do any partition.
germayne: what you saw just now in the iris is just from an illustration standpoint, right? That after transforming the data from four dimensions, I can visualize that, because I use two components, I can just do a mapping between C1 and C2, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: And what it's just trying to tell you is that, okay, I can also add the color. Then now, I asked you one question. The color, right? Where does the color come from? The color comes from the grouping, right? The Y label.
germayne: For unsupervised, do you have the Y label?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No.
germayne: Yeah, you don't have the white label.
germayne: Okay. Right.
germayne: What unsupervised gives you is unsupervised is just going to tell you that I have one group here, one group here, and one group here. What do they represent? I do not know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay. Right.
germayne: If you put in, let's say, a lot of data of a class, let's say, hypothetically, you guys are teachers. You guys, you know, maybe let's say I have some data of, like, every student in the school.
germayne: I want to do some kind of clustering. I put in things like…
germayne: the grades, I put in, like, the CCA scores, I put in, like, a lot of factors.
germayne: And it just tells me, like, okay, there's… there's 3 clusters.
germayne: Or 4 clusters. Does it tell me what does the cluster represent? No.
germayne: Maybe if I do some EDA, I check.
germayne: okay, all the data that is in this cluster, what do they have? Oh, in the EDA, it turns out that here, all of them, the family income is very high. Or maybe the cluster actually captures
germayne: the social-economic status. Or maybe if, let's say, I check the grades, the average grades are actually separated very well. Oh, maybe it's telling me that it's actually splitting by certain criteria. So, the problem with unsupervised is that it just gives you the cluster, it doesn't tell you the label.
germayne: The illustration earlier on, the color, right, is not for unsupervised, it's just PCA.
germayne: Telling you that I'm actually able to separate my data very nicely with respect to the Y-label. And why is it important?
germayne: Because if, let's say, I'm thinking about this from a predictive standpoint, all I'm saying is that maybe these two features.
germayne: allows me to predict my why, because I can partition them
germayne: in a different manner, right? I can cut them into this manner, right? If these two features allows me to cut them cleanly, then basically I can do a classification here, right? I can predict them… I can predict each of the flowers easily.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's a different thing. Understand? I don't understand why the example is bad.
germayne: Okay, I would say it's bad lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean, because the fact that today we start with PCA, so I get this impression that PCA is very important for unsupervised. I mean, my dead phone might take away lah.
germayne: No, no, but hope you don't have that takeaway now. This is just what we call this feature transformation, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: We talk about how do we actually find a mapping to represent data in different manner.
germayne: and we talk a bit about dimension reduction, right? Okay, but don't worry, don't worry, don't worry.
germayne: At the end.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: PCA is not as… so PCA, I can calculate PCA is not necessarily for unsupervised,
germayne: Certainly not necessary.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's a way of, like, it's like another, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Data classification, or the pre-processing of data, which you learned in the previous units,
germayne: Yes, yes, you can think of it that way. You are just transforming.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, okay.
germayne: from some M dimension to some N… sorry, from some N to some M dimension.
germayne: Right, so don't worry, don't worry, I think at the end, we will have a full chart, right? Don't worry so much, okay? Hopefully you understand, huh?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, because they're thinking coming in, so… Okay, okay, hang on.
germayne: Later, I'll show you guys some example lah, don't worry. Okay, so the last algo, right, is actually called dbscan. So what DBScan is that?
germayne: the idea of dbscan is we want to somehow group
germayne: the data based on the density. So the idea is that, let's say, if I have a lot of data.
germayne: I have a lot of data.
germayne: The idea is that
germayne: you know, I want to have some kind of grouping based on the density. Hey, maybe the density here is very good. This should be one cluster.
germayne: Correct? So it's a density base. So, basically, it means that if an area is highly dense, maybe there's a grouping that I can group something, right? And actually, you can see that density-based algo is actually very common.
germayne: Right? Why would you guys think, like, you know.
germayne: Any examples where you guys think, like, if anything in real life that is, like, highly cluttered, maybe I can talk about that. Anybody want to give me some intuition?
germayne: Try to guess, try to make some guess.
germayne: Can I relate density to real life or not?
germayne: What do you guys think?
germayne: So the context here is that density-based clustering The algorithm tries to find
germayne: Very dense area, and they are essentially called clusters.
germayne: Right?
germayne: But I want you guys to keep telling me, is there any…
germayne: Anything in real life where, actually, if there's a lot of things.
germayne: Actually, I can classify it as, you know, there's something there.
germayne: Hey, sorry, sorry, Lanson.
germayne: No, I cannot get it. What do you say?
germayne: Car park? Oh, so a lot of cars, is it?
Lim Hung (Lanson): Yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay. Yeah, that's a, that's a, that's a, that's a good example. Any… anything else?
germayne: So, so Lanson say, like, okay, if there's a lot of car, maybe there's something there. Like, hotspot, right? What else?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: People queuing for…
germayne: Basically.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: false.
germayne: Exactly. So, because you guys are now coming to my domain, right? So you guys are thinking in terms of geospatial, right?
germayne: From a geospatial map. If there are a lot of things, maybe there's some kind of hotspot there, correct? If there's a lot of people shopping, maybe there's certain hotspot. So you can see, actually, density-based clustering is very, very useful.
germayne: Okay? So what's the good thing about dbscan is that you don't have to define the number of clusters.
germayne: The algorithm itself determines how many
germayne: Density, how many clusters there are.
germayne: Okay? So, of course, you can see that because of the way… because of how the algorithm actually generates the cluster, you can see that it actually creates clusters in nonlinearly separatable data, which is a bit like something like that.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Okay, so people usually use this for anomaly detection as well, right? And of course, I gave some examples in real life, you can actually do this in real life, especially for geospatial data.
germayne: So, of course.
germayne: Not every algorithm is not so simple, right? It's not like, oh man, I don't have to define the clusters, I'm done. You have to define two parameters that is called the minimum number of points and epsilon.
germayne: Okay, I believe the notebook later will describe the algo.
germayne: But you can see here, right, that these two parameters actually determine
germayne: how you define has clusters. So, if you look at the circles here, essentially there's a few concepts to take away from here, right?
germayne: dbscan essentially has a concept called the core points, I call it CP.
germayne: You have the border points, BP, And you have the outliers.
germayne: So, essentially, you have two parameters here, right? You have epsilon.
germayne: And you have… so epsilon, you have epo… You have epsilon, And you have this minimum… Poise.
germayne: So what epsilon does is that epsilon basically defines the radius of the circle.
germayne: Right? And this radius of the circle will be used across each of your clusters.
germayne: Now, if you think about this, right, in reality.
germayne: if I want to apply this from a geospatial data, I think Lanson was saying, like, oh, I want to do it on Kapark. Maybe I want to look at where are the hotspots for people with their cars, right? I think Philip
germayne: And a few of them said about the number of people queuing, so you want to find, like, maybe areas where people are, right, human. So where do you think epsilon would look like? Epsilon then, if you relate in a real-world perspective, epsilon becomes, like, a distance in reality, right? Is it, like, X number of meters?
germayne: Correct? If you're applying in that context. So this defines the radius where I want to define my data points as core points, and the minimum number of points basically just says that if, you know, I draw a circle around every point.
germayne: what is the minimum number of pawns before I consider them as dense?
germayne: Right? So it may be, let's say, in your business criteria, you feel like, okay, to me, if I'm applying it on geospatial perspective.
germayne: I say that maybe 5 people is considered dense, then this will actually affect how you define the core points, as well as the border points. So essentially, the algorithm just basically checks every point, if there are a core point and a border point.
germayne: And if they are, Essentially, they become clusters.
germayne: And anybody that's outside just becomes outlier. Which is why, essentially, you can see here, everything just becomes a cluster, because everything is like a neighbor of a neighbor within their core point. So you're just drawing circles, and if everybody's a neighbor of neighbor, I'm able to move from one circle to another circle. Oh, I'm actually going to classify them as a cluster.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: The intuition for the alcode is actually quite straightforward, I'll just show you guys. If you guys are interested from an algorithm perspective, then you can just see this. I think the pseudocode is the easiest to understand.
germayne: Okay, I won't go through it, but you can just take away from here. So, here they have the algorithm here. So you can see the algorithm we just expressed here is actually very easy.
germayne: Right? The idea is that I'm just going to check every point, and if every point meets the number of minimum point, then okay, they're going to be a core point.
germayne: If not, then they're going to be an outlier. And what I then do is I check the neighbor of the point that is within the circle, because I draw the circle, right, using epsilon, and then I check if it has a minimum number of points. If it doesn't, and it's actually belonging to a neighbor of a core point, I'm going to call them a border point.
germayne: And I'm going to group all of these points into a cluster, and I'm going to iterate across every points, right? So if you look at the pseudocode here, right? Not going to go too deep into it, but the idea is that it gives you very nice clusters, right? And you don't have to define how many clusters, because it will automatically do it for you.
germayne: So, fantastic algorithm, I think I love it. Of course, we are teaching the basic. There's actually a newer algorithm called HDB Scan.
germayne: But the idea still follows.
germayne: Okay, so I'll just show something.
germayne: So there's actually a very old block from GoJack, just show you. So this is a block that is written very long ago, so I'm not exposing any secret.
germayne: So you can see here, right, the idea is that
germayne: I think just like some of you guys have the intuition, you can use it to look at people, look at bookings, look at car, right? So the idea here is that you can actually apply this in a geospatial perspective. If a lot of people drop off customers at a certain point, maybe I can use it to pick up customers.
germayne: Right? So I can use it using clustering algorithm. Okay? So you can see here, that dbscan is also one algo that can be used.
germayne: Right? You can see that we can find clusters automatically at popular locations, right? You can also use k-means as well, right? You can also use k-means to use to identify certain pickup locations, right? Of course, then you have to use other metrics to measure whether these clusters is correct.
germayne: Okay, I'm not going to go through too deep in here, this is open, you can just Google… easily Google this, right? Just Google DPScan, GoJack, and you can find it.
germayne: And, by the way, this is outdated already lah, so… so there's no secret that's exposed, right? But you can see that clustering is useful. It's not that… it's not that it's not useful, but the challenge is how do you interpret it, right? If your goal is to simply use it to partition something, you don't care.
germayne: Right? And you want to use the partition to have some kind of business logic, then maybe interpretation is not important to you.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, you can see here, lah, geospatial, you can cluster earthquakes, you can use to cluster natural disaster. DBScan is also often used in anomaly detection.
germayne: customer segmentation, you can also use other algo, but I would say geospatial is very, very relevant for DBScan, because, you know, human, in reality, for a lot of highly dense areas, we think about them from a density standpoint, right?
germayne: Okay? So, these are some of the use cases for the algorithm. So it's not like, just because you cannot interpret means they are useless. Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think just to summarize, we've gone through 3 types of, algorithm, very common algorithm.
germayne: Just to re-emphasize, K means you need to define the K, but later you can see that we have some methods to help you determine K, but please take note, that is measured
germayne: Using the inertial perspective doesn't guarantee correctness for your business.
germayne: Spherical, also very sensitive to outlier, therefore you need to scale them.
germayne: You can have distance metric, you can choose the distance metric. By default, users, you clean distance, right?
germayne: And if you know that your data is spherical, then of course, kmines will work perfectly. And again, right, the intuition here is that how do you actually know that the data is spherical?
germayne: If you are just using it on your business use case, of course it might not… you might not know the data, but I think this applies to a lot of systems, either from a mathematical standpoint, from a physics standpoint, or from a finance standpoint, where maybe there's enough study to actually show that there are some spherical property for the data.
germayne: then you know that, oh, K-Me's actually worked for it. Otherwise, it's just purely empirical.
germayne: similar to what you do in your Kaggle, that, in theory, There are some…
germayne: Knowledge that you can use in terms of determining what are the knobs to tweak.
germayne: But in practice, you have to do it from an empirical standpoint, which means you've got to try out from an experiment.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Of course, you can see here there's a hard clustering assignment. Hard clustering basically just say that it's just assigning the… each of the data points directly into the cluster. There are, of course, soft clustering methods, which means they give them a probability score, right? But of course, cadence is not one of them.
germayne: Second one we talk about is hierarchical clustering. Again, we talk a bit about the top-down and the bottom-up, but of course, bottom-up is the most common one.
germayne: Again, the methodology from the algorithm is that it assumes everybody is an individual cluster, then it starts to group them one by one.
germayne: How do you actually group them? You determine the distance again. What should I define the distance? And the second thing you need to choose is the linkage. How do I define what is close? How do I define close? Is it the closest neighbor, or is it the furthest neighbor? Right?
germayne: Again, the dendrogram lets you cut the clusters. So if, let's say, you want an algorithm that gives you all the clusters, and you want to choose the lever of which cluster you want to expand into, hierarchical clustering will be the good one for you.
germayne: Okay? And then finally, we talk about DBScan. I think it's my personal favorite. DBScan is, of course, the basic one. Now, people start to also create HDB scan.
germayne: Out of topic, but you guys can look into it.
germayne: Able to handle outliers, because one of the groupings will be outlier.
germayne: automatically determine the number of clusters based on the density, right? And it is deterministic because you need to tweak what is epsilon and what is the minimum number of points.
germayne: If it's a geospatial standpoint, my recommendation is you can actually use real-life distance, if you use, like, a distance matrix that is actually called a metric that is something like harvesting distance, for example. Harvard sign distance is like a mapping on meters, for example, in real life, right?
germayne: Of course, you need to define these two parameters, and it will then be able to create
germayne: The cluster mappings, and it uses the concept of core points, border points, and outliers.
germayne: So, from an overall standpoint, actually, you can see the algorithm, not super difficult, but challenge is how do you actually use it?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I, I think, stop here first.
germayne: Anybody has any questions so far for the unsupervised? So, actually, that's all for unsupervised, and now if you look at the takeaway, you guys actually saw what I did, right?
germayne: Actually, all the algo… oh, sorry.
germayne: all the algo actually maps from X to a partition, correct?
germayne: So basically, it tells me…
germayne: given a data point, should it belong in group 1, Group 2, Group 3, whatever, depending on what you define. So it just gives you that, and you have no target label. So what you need to do is, if you have the partition, you just need to use your X data to do the EDA to determine the statistics. How do I interpret each of the partitions?
germayne: Alright?
germayne: Okay, I think there is… okay. Okay, I think thanks, thanks, thanks, Elvin, for sharing. I think Alvin is, like, sharing a lot of materials for you guys to… to see, so thanks for that, yeah? Okay.
Dr Alvin Ang(2nd device): We'll call.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: yeah. That's something.
germayne: Yes, of course. Welcome, yeah, you are free to ask. You ask, you ask, ask while you can.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because I, I just… so, you know, we learn logistic, regression, right? Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, I had to differentiate the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because that one, you also choose, I mean, it's a classification, right? That one is also a classification.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yes. So that one, I need to differentiate differently from here, because…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That one has a Y, this one doesn't have a Y.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. You have the why. I can measure what is correctness, but here you can't measure. Yeah. Because what is correct to you in your data set.
germayne: can be… can have different interpretation, right? As a partition, I can have a lot of different interpretations. If, let's say, you have the customer data, you are doing customer segmentation, how do I define which are the cluster? Maybe you can say here is low spender, here is high spender.
germayne: But…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's correct. But in a way, there's also something stopping me from making one of these clusters the Y also, right?
germayne: making one of these clusters a Y.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I want to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: let's say I want to, like, you know, I mean, I clustered them and partitioned it already, then I decided that, hey, maybe…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I want to measure the, you know, because the, the, in, in logistic or linear, right, the Y and X is tough to me to choose. I mean, based on what I learned so far, what I understand so far.
germayne: Yes, it's.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I can make my… one of these clusters my Y, and the other one my X also Y.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This, this one.
germayne: But why would you want to do that in this case? So let's say if you all…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I wouldn't want to do that, but I could do that lah. And for now, I could do that, but why is another reason, another questionnah.
germayne: So, so I think your, your one is the opposite direction, right? You are doing unsupervised, so let's say you have a partition.
germayne: Let me draw here.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, assuming I do not know my data, I mean, I do not.
germayne: So you have a partition, and then you say you want to use the partition as Y. I think it's the opposite. So what people usually do, right, is either you use this as supervised, or you do this as… sorry, you do this as unsupervised, and then you do this as supervised. What I was saying is that some people, because they have X and Y,
germayne: Right? Some people, they use X to create a partition.
germayne: Right? Now, what you do is, the partition data, along with the X data.
germayne: They are using it as additional features to predict why.
germayne: They are doing that. People do that as well.
germayne: But you don't use the partition as your why. Like, what's the point of doing that? You understand what I mean? Okay. So this is just… so… but I think the whole point that I think I told you… I told you, I'm telling you guys, is that, end of the day, these are just tools, right? You can…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah.
germayne: You can really be very creative, and I think I gave you guys a lot of very creative
germayne: insights about using certain stuff. I think last week I told you guys about the… the… you can just do normalization on your… on your regression problem to make it classification, but people does that as well.
germayne: So, so there's really a lot of… a lot of things. As long as it's correct, right, it makes sense. As in, from a theory standpoint.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Got it right?
germayne: So, I think what I'll do is, don't worry, at the end, right, when we go through everything in Module 3, I'll give you guys the ultimate mind map.
germayne: Okay, I'll give you guys the ultimate mind map of what is the difference between each of the topics. I'll give you guys that at the end.
germayne: Okay? Because it doesn't make sense that I repeat this multiple times again and again. So, at the very end, I'll tell you from 3.1 all the way to 3.10,
germayne: from this overall structure, from a data science standpoint, where does it sit? What's the difference? I'll tell you guys one by one, again, towards the end.
germayne: Okay, and you can see that, actually.
germayne: If I draw them side by side and compare them, you will see that it's actually very different, correct? It's not that… I won't know when to use unsupervised versus supervised. You will know, because you don't have the target label.
germayne: Okay? And if you don't have the target label, how do you define correct? You cannot define correctness. So the algorithm basically has its own definition of what is.
germayne: what is closed and what is far, right? Correct? Because it doesn't have a label. K-means basically say that, okay, please be near the centroid.
germayne: dbscan basically has its own mechanism to determine what is an outlier or not, but you realize that they don't have an idea of what is correct.
germayne: So, has opposed to supervised learning, mathematically, it doesn't have a loss function to optimize, right? It's not an optimization process where, oh, I'm just going to minimize my prediction to be as accurate as possible, it doesn't have that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, so in a way, you're saying, like, no matter how I… you need… we need to know the why lah. I mean, if you don't know the why, then there's no point in continuing.
germayne: No, I'm not saying that, Noel.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No.
germayne: If, of course, you have your Y label, you can easily do unsupervised, easily. But if you don't have it.
germayne: Right? Then… And you want some kind of grouping, then you do unsupervised.
germayne: It's a two… it's two different purpose. One is to just group into groups, one is to make a prediction, given certain input data. It's different.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay…
germayne: Right.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, I think, I think, I think, yeah, no, don't worry, you'll think about it, let's discuss again on Saturday, okay? Just take some time to absorb. Take some time to absorb.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Thank you.
germayne: Today, okay, no problem. Okay, I think what we will do is, I'll just let Soon take over.
germayne: if you guys need to go toilet, just go for it, okay? So that I don't think we will have an official break, but if you guys need a toilet break, just go, right? I'll just hand over to soon. So we'll use the remaining time for the 3L go.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so if you guys just need to go, then just feel free to just go to the washroom, it's okay, yeah?
germayne: Okay, if there's any questions, we will continue on Saturday.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Sorry, sorry. I mean, you guys can ask the questions anytime, like, it's not like we can… but we can talk about it deeper on Saturday.
germayne: Yeah, okay, I'll just let Soon… Take overall.
germayne: F.
Soon | NTU: Give me a second, Anatomy.
Soon | NTU: Adjusted,
Soon | NTU: Right, let's continue with our Jupyter notebook. Now,
Soon | NTU: please go to the outline, right, and then proceed to the k-means, clustering section.
Soon | NTU: Okay, clustering, yeah. So, right from here, let's scroll down…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so to illustrate this, how the k-means work.
Soon | NTU: Okay, we will make use of the…
Soon | NTU: Iris dataset, like, so that we do not want to use another defense set to make everything so confusing, right? You know how to better relate to whatever we have done before. Anyway, Iris dataset is a very popular dataset, so I think by now, some of you would have already,
Soon | NTU: let's say, gotten a lot of hands-on, you know, know what this data set is all about, right? So, for the built-in dataset of, Seabourn.
Soon | NTU: This dataset has only 150 rows.
Soon | NTU: by 5 column, okay? So what we're trying to do is,
Soon | NTU: Similar to what we have done in a PCA, right, we are trying to make use of k-means, clustering technique to
Soon | NTU: this data point, right, into their respective cluster, okay? As to how many clusters, that one, we will talk about it later, okay? So.
Soon | NTU: Visually, we will want to see okay.
Soon | NTU: Kleemio, Randy Sagina.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's plot the… data point, using the scatter plot, and see… now, this is the…
Soon | NTU: how the data point looks like, but of course, for simplicity, we choose to use the pattern length and sample
Soon | NTU: a length to… for you to visualize, right? Okay, so let's focus on the k-means clustering algorithm first, right? So, based on the k-means, right, we are going to see
Soon | NTU: compare, right? So this is our baseline, our starting point, okay? So all these species are coming, right.
Soon | NTU: From your dataset, right?
Soon | NTU: That means they are the model answer, lah, no, they can't be wrong, right? Now, if we… okay, so we just extract the four numeric column, right? We need to discard the label column when we use a clustering algorithm, like k-means.
Soon | NTU: Right, because… This is, distance space algorithm, so you cannot fit in, something like… Where is it?
Soon | NTU: Cetosa, Basicola, and so on, okay, so all these subtasks. And there's no need for us to do any encoding, because there is no need to do just the encoding in the clustering algorithm.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we will go through… Import the k-means class.
Soon | NTU: From the cluster module.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And then, as a stop, let's…
Soon | NTU: Because we already know there are three, iris species in a data set. Okay, so let's start with…
Soon | NTU: A number of clusters as 3.
Soon | NTU: Okay, set a random seat so that your result can be… you can reproduce it, you know, so that you will not change when you run it multiple times, right?
Soon | NTU: And then… Train a model by calling the feed method, and then…
Soon | NTU: You will see there are 3
Soon | NTU: cluster. These are called the centroid. Okay, so these are the center of the cluster.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, but… because we have four features, right? So, each of these
Soon | NTU: This is the centroid, the center point of this first cluster.
Soon | NTU: Because Python is zero-way, so first cluster is cluster zero.
Soon | NTU: Castle 1.
Soon | NTU: And then cluster 2.
Soon | NTU: We have 3 clusters, right, remember?
Soon | NTU: Now, these three clusters can be…
Soon | NTU: Okay, these quick hustles are the one
Soon | NTU: Okay, these centroids are the ones, created by the k-means after you have gone through all your data points, right? Just how you've seen how the k-means, they are basically a few steps, right?
Soon | NTU: Amen.
Soon | NTU: This is the end result.
Soon | NTU: K-means will predict for each of your data points, there are 150 data points, okay? Based on the first data point.
Soon | NTU: All the dimension, length, and width.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And based on the distance formula.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so he has identified this data point belong to Cluster 1.
Soon | NTU: The second customer.
Soon | NTU: And so on, okay? Now, if you were to plot this.
Soon | NTU: On the scatter plot, okay, you will see something like this.
Soon | NTU: So these are the… 3 Centroi.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Now, even though there are four features, they are supposed to have four dimensions, right? But for simplicity, we choose to use only two dimensions to show you the results, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, now, we have already seen earlier that the ground truth
Soon | NTU: Based on the actual data set, right?
Soon | NTU: It is, like, there's… Okay? So without using k-means, this is the actual so-called the cluster…
Soon | NTU: for each of these data points, okay, so we have some… This is a green…
Soon | NTU: cluster, this orange cluster, and the blue cluster, okay? So, now, if this cluster are not color-coded, okay.
Soon | NTU: Visually, you will have guessed the only two.
Soon | NTU: cluster, right?
Soon | NTU: But because there are some,
Soon | NTU: Color in it, so you know, oh, even though there's some overlap here.
Soon | NTU: you still know there are 3 clusters, okay, because it is already understood the data set has 3 clusters, okay? Now, comparing this
Soon | NTU: to the… Okay, comparing this to the,
Soon | NTU: what we have obtained after applying the KME clustering, okay? It looked very similar, Right.
Soon | NTU: Zero cluster, 1 and 2, like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, but I think there are some differences
Soon | NTU: Over here, okay? Because in the original scatterplot, there's some overlap between
Soon | NTU: The cluster 0 and cluster 2.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is what, how we can use the k-means to…
Soon | NTU: Do clustering of your data point.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Any questions?
Teng Lee LIM: Hey, why is the cluster not live?
Teng Lee LIM: It should be street color, right?
Soon | NTU: spherical.
Teng Lee LIM: Anyways.
Soon | NTU: If your data points are spherical, of course, it would be spherical, lah, but if your data points are not spherical, then your sphere is…
Soon | NTU: Something like this, lah.
Teng Lee LIM: Yeah, but then, like, if you look at the center data, right, if I were to draw an equal distance circular around it.
Teng Lee LIM: It got a different radius lah. Then I thought it would overlap with the other data set.
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes, you're right. Okay, there's some overlap between what you have here in the cluster 0, as well as the data point in the cluster 2.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that's why in the later cook blogs, right, you will see there's actually some kind of,
Soon | NTU: differences between what the, chart will tell you, which are… what is the optimal K we should choose
Soon | NTU: to use for the k-means.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, so, so leave this question of overlapping cluster, okay, for the timing, and then let's proceed.
Soon | NTU: to the next, okay? So, when we talk about the elbow method, and also the silhouette, score method, okay, then we will
Soon | NTU: have a chance to explore, okay, actually, should we use K equal to 3, or should there be another number that will give you the better clustering pattern?
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, if you look at the, k-means formula, right? Okay, so just now, you have already learned k-means
Soon | NTU: Each of the…
Soon | NTU: K that you have used for the K means to group your data set, okay? So, in the case of our example, we started off with using the K equal to 3, right?
Soon | NTU: So, after you cluster all the data points into three groups.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and then your model initial
Soon | NTU: This attribute will give you a number.
Soon | NTU: This number, of course, Okay, it represents the sum of squared distances
Soon | NTU: Of the data point to their closest cluster center.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so another name for the… Initial is called a… Wcss game.
Soon | NTU: It is called within Cluster sum of square.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, if it's within the class of sum of squared, it means you only assess… you only calculate this
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Based on one cluster.
Soon | NTU: You are not going to, you know, check, you know, how far this point in cluster 1, right.
Soon | NTU: to the… This point in cluster zero.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is not the, what this K means to look at, yeah. You only look at the initial by calculating how each of these data points are from this clause here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and then do a… Square, and then sum it up.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is the, initial, okay? Now.
Soon | NTU: We can make use of this initial, okay, to determine the optimal K, okay, but before we do that, right, using the LU method and Siliac score method, okay, let's explore manually, using
Soon | NTU: another value for your K.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… Let's try creating
Soon | NTU: a cluster with, using K-means with 6 clusters. So, at the end of this came in.
Soon | NTU: Clustering, you should be able to see 6 clusters in your scatterplot.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is how you define… 6… And then… You are blinders.
Soon | NTU: Predict, and you'll get this
Soon | NTU: Okay, so when you see this predict, right, it doesn't mean that you, be using it for
Soon | NTU: 8, classification, so-called this, model.
Soon | NTU: Okay, we… we are basically using it to…
Soon | NTU: applying on the existing dataset, okay, but by modifying this, because K means already know Okay.
Soon | NTU: your own data set.
Soon | NTU: after you have fitted it in here. Yeah, fit means you have trained, this K means to
Soon | NTU: Calculate the initial for each of the clusters.
Soon | NTU: Dean.
Soon | NTU: And because of that, it knows each of these data points belong to each cluster, okay? But to get this, we basically will call the predict method.
Soon | NTU: Of the model.
Soon | NTU: Okay, but we are not implying that we are using it for prediction and also for predicting unseen data in the future. Okay, no, we are not,
Soon | NTU: Okay, employing that, right? We are basically getting the, cluster Number.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: After training.
Soon | NTU: Because we have modified the number cluster into 6, okay? So…
Soon | NTU: Plotting the data point with some coloring using the scatter plot will show a chart like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… This chart is,
Soon | NTU: What does it tell you based on the result you've seen in the scatter plot?
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So maybe I can…
Soon | NTU: Estho daisone.
Soon | NTU: Right. What, what does it…
Soon | NTU: what does the scatterport tell you? Okay, so if you have 6 clusters versus just now you have 3 clusters, okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Does this, cluster the K equal to 6, huh? Give you a better… Option.
Soon | NTU: Okay? To so-call your… dissect your data so that you can split it nicely into 6 groups.
Soon | NTU: What do you think?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: If we start off knowing that there are only 3 species, by splitting to 6 levels, right, you are making it a lot more complicated already, isn't it?
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes. Okay, very, very good answer, Philip. So, we, we are actually overcasting. Okay, in this case, we are… we already know the model answer, okay? So, this is not something, we would like to do, overcastering of our data point, okay? So.
Soon | NTU: If it's 3 is optimal, then use 3 lah.
Soon | NTU: Rather than… You have to really split the… this group.
Soon | NTU: This is a setosa, right? Again, it is a very distinct cluster already, with a K equal to 3, but now we are trying to split it further. Maybe there is a pattern somewhere, but I think
Soon | NTU: may… may not be necessary in this case, okay? Now, so now, the question now is.
Soon | NTU: what determine… are we able to determine the optimal K, all right?
Soon | NTU: In the case of the Iris dataset, we already know it in advance, okay? So, what are the techniques that we can use to
Soon | NTU: For us to, let's say, use to predict what is the
Soon | NTU: optimal K, right, before we even start to use a k-means to cluster our data, okay? Because this is a chicken egg, right? Before you tell k-means to do something, you have to provide the hyperparameter for k-means, right? To start off.
Soon | NTU: K is 3. Okay, then k-means will take this, and then try to find whether there are 3 distinct
Soon | NTU: group in your data point, okay? So now, this code block is to iterate
Soon | NTU: to the different value of K, okay, from 2 to 7.
Soon | NTU: 2 to 7, usually we ignore the last number in the range method, okay? So 2 to 7, for each of the value, we will calculate,
Soon | NTU: The initial, and then store it, and plot it out.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Maybe make it smaller.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So, you'll see a chart like this. Okay, so… Now, the optimal K… Is the one that will…
Soon | NTU: We hear, okay, when you're…
Soon | NTU: Initial, this is the initial, right? The vertical axis, the horizontal is the K, okay? So, of course.
Soon | NTU: the more K, the higher the K, the lower the initial, right? Because it is overfitting your model already, right?
Soon | NTU: You'll have more, more cluster, okay? So, but… Mon…
Soon | NTU: cluster doesn't mean it's good. Okay, sometimes you can also say, oh, why not we use a K equal to 20, okay? If you have a K equal to 20, then you will have a problem when trying to analyze your data, okay? You'll be too high to be useful for your data analysis, okay? Now.
Soon | NTU: The optimal k will be 3, will be a point.
Soon | NTU: Where your rate of decrease of your initial is at the steepest.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is what we call the elbow method.
Soon | NTU: Right? You can see there's an elbow here, right? You know, there's a… I will…
Soon | NTU: Right? So you can see, elbow method will tell you optimal K is 3.
Soon | NTU: So, which is quite aligned to the actual number of species, iris species, that we have in our dataset, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So, what is the other technique for us to determine the optimal K? That is called the silhouette score, right? Now, applying the same logic.
Soon | NTU: Right? We iterate through… From 2 to 7.
Soon | NTU: Using this code, and then store the silhouette score for each of the K values.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And this is what we can.
Soon | NTU: For KS2, you have the highest LGAD score, And then…
Soon | NTU: K3 is about 0.55, and so on. Okay, so you can see that Is it? Which…
Soon | NTU: Is the value okay? That gave you the optimal Clustification, clustering performance.
Soon | NTU: Based on this, silhouette score.
Soon | NTU: Okay, severe score is… the… Higher, the better lah. Okay, the max is, 1. So the silhouette score…
Soon | NTU: will range from minus 1 to 1. Of course, we are trying to get,
Soon | NTU: Close to 1 as much as possible, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so based on this chart.
Soon | NTU: What should be the K value that you should choose?
Soon | NTU: for your Kmis.
Soon | NTU: So where, you wanna try?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Actually, I thought it was 3, but now, when I look at this thing, too, like, bacteria.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because the rest, like, a bit too… Too many.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah. So, I think there's some, okay, so some Italian, right?
Soon | NTU: elbow methods say K equal to 3 is the best, right?
Soon | NTU: But serious scores say 2 is the best.
Soon | NTU: So, if there is such a…
Soon | NTU: discrepancy, right? So, so which one do you choose?
Soon | NTU: Because we already know the answer lah, okay, so we likely would choose 3, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is that 30, son.
Soon | NTU: But…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I studied examples, like, oh, this one's not very good. Nevermind, never mind.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so when there are two… some differences between the silhouette score, what the silhouette score tell you, the K, versus what you get from the elbow method, okay, so…
Soon | NTU: I would say your ciluit score usually Work a few more.
Soon | NTU: so you will have more parity, because you get a score look at in… Okay.
Soon | NTU: elbow method, the initial, only look at, the within cluster sum of squared, right? Silver score look at inter-cluster
Soon | NTU: quality of your, your, your coloring, okay? So, it is giving more information than what the elbow matter can, give. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: You can choose two, because you, visually, you can see that this group 1 and 2 at the top, right?
Soon | NTU: if I don't color it, you would have,
Soon | NTU: Thought there are actually two classes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Yeah. So… if we use another, dataset, not Iris, right, probably… I may also choose tool.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But let's say I'm quite, quite, quite jailed, right? Can you imagine that I do all the work, then I realize that, oh, it's 2, but then I realized, oh, actually, it's not 2, it's actually 3. What are my… won't, like, all the effort be wasted?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Like, why would everyone want to do this?
Soon | NTU: Sometimes you also have to align to, whatever your business needs are.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean, let's say, let's say the business is as clueless as you, I know they're looking at you for direction, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then you do, do, do, yeah, you know, yeah, I said, yeah, this, you explain the cluster, you know, you say, yeah, this one will tell you to separate it nicely and everything. And you say, okay, then along the way, go, go, then I realized, then towards the end, you realize, actually, it's not 2, no, actually, yeah…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: She… no way, it says she's 3 years, so…
Soon | NTU: So, the interpretation of the cluster that are formed by the clustering algorithm, okay, is very important. So, can you really, tell, let's say, what is cluster zero?
Soon | NTU: Why is Castle 1?
Soon | NTU: And, you know, what makes them so different from the other cluster? So, you really have to…
Soon | NTU: Look at the data, and then…
Soon | NTU: Makes sense out of this cluster.
Soon | NTU: Because k-means will only know how to segregate the cluster by some distance formula.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so only we can tell, you know, how to group data, yeah.
Soon | NTU: So maybe, oh, these are… Customer, they're, wealthy, you know, but yet they are not…
Soon | NTU: they don't have a high frequency in their purchase, so you can roughly gauge what… how you should, label your cluster. Instead of cluster 0, you have some name to it. I think in the Module 2, I think some group, right, is it Team 1? You have already tagged your
Soon | NTU: a product with some, name, right? Okay, some pattern there. Okay, so this is something we need to do after the clustering, using your
Soon | NTU: We do… Real… the normal review.
Soon | NTU: Right? Something like that, right? You have to interpret
Soon | NTU: Human in the loop, you have to come in for their interpretation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yo, how is this… the more I think about this, the more it looks like… like ADA, you know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe a bit more Q method, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But it's an ADA, you know, I couldn't, you know, group data until I can understand the data better, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This one, like, is helping me do that, rather than…
Soon | NTU: You get the clustering algorithm to give you the, so-called the first cut.
Soon | NTU: You know, because if you have too many dimensions, too many features, it is visually impossible for you to visualize your data point, how it looks like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So that's why we need the clustering algorithm to help us.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Do you help us cut it out and angle.
Soon | NTU: Conjunction with your PCA, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, so it's late.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let's…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: go through it, because we only have, 20 minutes. Okay, so with the stereot score, we have.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay?
Soon | NTU: this is a different, dataset, okay? Now, we have already, Okay?
Soon | NTU: we noticed there's some, difference in the optimal K, based on the elbow method, and also based on the silhouette score, okay? So…
Soon | NTU: And…
Soon | NTU: Depending on the business, so-called use case, we just sort of choose one that is appropriate for the
Soon | NTU: Maybe for the… Marketing campaign, right?
Soon | NTU: So likely that you will choose a group that is not too many.
Soon | NTU: And also not too fear lah, right?
Soon | NTU: If you have two groups, then… I think…
Soon | NTU: An ideal number would be somewhere in the region of, 3 to 6, huh?
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Now, next we have,
Soon | NTU: Another exercise on the… using the k-mains on this cost… more customer data set, right? So this is a CAGO dataset.
Soon | NTU: And… I will suggest… Let's go through the code, yeah, very quickly.
Soon | NTU: So now, you can find this in your…
Soon | NTU: In your folder, get the more customer… Okay.
Soon | NTU: Very small dataset, with only… 200 roll by.
Soon | NTU: 5 column.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And then we know…
Soon | NTU: Just a simple sanity check on the dataset. We know there are actually no, column or row with a missing value.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Now, we just want to visualize how the
Soon | NTU: the data set looked like, yeah, using the scatter plot, by plotting Annual income, which is… Spending school.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you can roughly tell how many groups are there.
Soon | NTU: Although… 5, right, visually.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now, we don't include the other dimension into the scatter plot yet. So, based on these two, you can tell there are five distinct groups.
Soon | NTU: Right, even though… There are only 4 here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so they have financing group.
Soon | NTU: And then… Let's see… Okay, be safe for…
Soon | NTU: Because I think they group everything together at the bottom.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's use the k-means with 4 as a starting number.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: To group the data.
Soon | NTU: And then we use…
Soon | NTU: only choose this numeric column for our chemist, okay? Because, for the other two columns, customer ID and gender.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: customer ID, why, why do we exclude it?
Soon | NTU: Why do we escort the customer ID?
Soon | NTU: Even though it is an integer.
Hitesh shah: It's not a feature, right?
Soon | NTU: Sorry?
Hitesh shah: It's not a feature.
Hitesh shah: It's just a…
Hitesh shah: There's not a feature of.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Probably just running number.
Hitesh shah: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, if it's a column in the dev set, usually we call it a feature lah, but it's only a question of whether that feature is useful.
Soon | NTU: for your, you know, when you train a machine learning model, okay? So, for customer ID, usually we won't include it, because this is a high cardinality feature, okay?
Soon | NTU: if I have 1 million row, this one will have 1 million unique value. So, what is there? There is actually no pattern, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So, high cardinality. Gender is because this is, Alphanumerate.
Soon | NTU: Of course, if you find useful, You can use,
Soon | NTU: one whole encoding to include it, okay? But for simplicity, we just choose the annual income and the spending score, okay? And then we choose an optimal… not an optimal, just a test
Soon | NTU: The k-means, we've just… Using k equal to 4 as a starting point, right?
Soon | NTU: This numeric column.
Soon | NTU: And then, we will… train our k-means with these three numeric column.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: We have four… Centroid.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: For each of the, clusters.
Soon | NTU: So this is for you to review what you have provided for k-means, okay? So the other two columns are removed.
Soon | NTU: the customer ID and agenda.
Soon | NTU: No.
Soon | NTU: Now we go through the, make use of the Stilua score to check, is it really true that our optimal K is equal to 4?
Soon | NTU: Right? So we just iterate through From 2 to 10.
Soon | NTU: And then, let's see… Okay, so we have this.
Soon | NTU: puddings, Side by side, okay, so now can you…
Soon | NTU: Tell me what should be the optimal value for your K.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you look at it, right, it should be 6, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if I go to choose, I would choose 6 now. Okay, so 6…
Soon | NTU: Right? So that is why we have this cluster equal to 6, And then we choose it.
Soon | NTU: to rerun our k-means.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is similar to what we have done in the linear regression. After you're going through all the hyperparameter tuning, get the best part
Soon | NTU: In this case, it's k equal to 6th, and then we retrain our k-means
Soon | NTU: with the same data set, and then get the result, okay? So this is the final result.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Right? So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we still have two more algorithms to go through. Okay, so let's,
Soon | NTU: quickly go through what we have, the EBS scan, how do we use it to.
Soon | NTU: cluster our data. Okay, so in this case, we have…
Soon | NTU: to import the DBS scan also from the scikit-learn.
Soon | NTU: cluster module.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Likewise, you can get more information, and of course, you can also go to the Sakit Learn
Soon | NTU: official website to… Get more detailed information of the…
Soon | NTU: various hyperparameter of a DBS scan, okay? So, now, for DBS scan, the two important hyperparameters are
Soon | NTU: The epsilon and the minimum sample, okay? So, epsilon is the distance
Soon | NTU: Of each of the data points, right?
Soon | NTU: profile.
Soon | NTU: within the 0.6. Okay, so we are using the IRIS dataset, so this 0.6 is 0.6 CM.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so within the 0.6, how many data points are within A circle of 0.6.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So, you have to see. Now, if you have more than four.
Soon | NTU: point within the circle of 0.6CM, okay? So, you…
Soon | NTU: As a data point, it's called a con.
Soon | NTU: call upon, right?
Soon | NTU: If it's less, then it's called a border point. Otherwise, it is called a noise, right? Outliers.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we go through the fitting.
Soon | NTU: training the DBS scan, and then this is the end result, okay? Now, one thing to notice is, because
Soon | NTU: DPS scan is slightly different from K-Means, okay? So, for outlier.
Soon | NTU: It will say it is an outlier. You don't belong to any other group.
Soon | NTU: Okay, whereas for k-means, if there's an outlier, k-means will, you know, we track it to the nearest cluster, even though it may or may not make sense. Okay, that outlier may or may not belong to that cluster, okay? So, as you can see.
Soon | NTU: There are 1, 2… tree.
Soon | NTU: 4… about Fiverr.
Soon | NTU: Based on this, prediction, you can see there are 5 negatives. So that is the, convention the scikit-learn library uses.
Soon | NTU: Minus 1 is to denote the outline data point.
Soon | NTU: in DBS Scan.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: Any question for the DBS game?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let me go through the, the last part is… Now, for this,
Soon | NTU: hierarchical clustering, right? So, basically, what…
Soon | NTU: The graph that we can get, right, after the clustering is completed, I mean, especially a tree like this.
Soon | NTU: Invert the tree.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so then you will see, oh, you know, these are the…
Soon | NTU: At the lowest level are the data points.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And then slowly, the…
Soon | NTU: clustering algorithm will group all the data points based on some similarity, based on your distance metrics as what this journey may have gone through, right? Depending on what you have chosen to define your
Soon | NTU: The… the… the similarity, right, for your…
Soon | NTU: clustering algorithm, okay? So then your data point will be grouped like this.
Soon | NTU: Beautiful tree.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so how you should interpret this is…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is the detail.
Soon | NTU: hope, okay, but I won't go through line by line, okay? But I'll just have to show
Soon | NTU: Explain to you how you actually cut that.
Soon | NTU: horizontal line.
Soon | NTU: in order to choose the number of classes, okay? So, if you look at this, So this,
Soon | NTU: Hierarchical clustering also tells you that There are only two.
Soon | NTU: customer, based on the coloring, right? Now, if you look at this particular bar, right.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, the longer the bar, okay.
Soon | NTU: the less similar between this group versus this, okay? So if you look at this, right, the bar is very short.
Soon | NTU: It shows that there's still some similarity between the groups here, okay? As you go up, you'll have longer and longer bar.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So… You will try to… just see what is the best, right? You will not cut at this
Soon | NTU: Because this is still very… Sean.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So, we will try to cut at the long bar.
Soon | NTU: the first long bandia we can find, okay? But try to apply on the actual data set, because, for every dataset, we only know it's 3.
Soon | NTU: You can also cut it here, too. If you cut it here, it'll be too many already.
Soon | NTU: Forecaster here at this line, somewhere at the… Equal to… Your, your distance is 4.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is how you, interpret the, dendrogram.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Which is the, usually the… the graph
Soon | NTU: Output by the hierarchical clustering algorithm.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and then, making use of this, you can also use this hierarchical clustering tool.
Soon | NTU: cluster your IRIS dataset in this, okay?
Soon | NTU: It won't be… Similar to your KMIs, because…
Soon | NTU: your SMY are totally different, okay? Try to change your…
Soon | NTU: X and Y, horizontal and vertical axes, and see whether you can find some similarity between your k-means and your hierarchical customing results, right? So I will leave it,
Soon | NTU: For your homework, yeah. So, any questions,
Soon | NTU: you may post it in your Discord, okay?
Soon | NTU: Right, so that is the end of the Jupyter Notebook, session.
Soon | NTU: So, in the interest of time, you may pose your question in the Discord. I'll be more than happy to answer the questions, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, I just wanted to ask one question, the last…
Chieh Cheng Lai: the last, clustering, actually, the parameters, they are different, I'm checking, because, the one on the y-axis is the, sample width, the other one is the petal length, and the,
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, then the x-axis, for this one is a separate length, then the other one… yeah, there are… the… I mean, yeah, X and Y axis are different. Definitely the… the cluster will… the shape of the cluster will look different.
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes, you're right, charging. This, access are not really the same, okay, so… I think…
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me try.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is, pedal length versus silver length.
Soon | NTU: All right.
Soon | NTU: But because of the different algorithm, so you will see slightly different way the data points are clustered.
Soon | NTU: In your final scatterplot.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, I mean that if this is the case, definitely will be different from the k-means, because
Chieh Cheng Lai: they use the… the XY… I mean, XY axis, they are different. So, I mean, the important point is the…
Chieh Cheng Lai: the number of clusters will be the key issue. It doesn't matter, how they are distributed. For my case, I just concerned about that they are well, separated and clustered. I don't care how they are positioned.
Chieh Cheng Lai: whether they are similar as a performer for the chemists, in between these two, goals.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so from the chart, do you get a very distinct cluster?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, from the above one, there is 3 clusters, and below this one also had 3 clusters.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, okay. So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so with this distinct cluster, if you do not see any… a lot of overlaps, that means at least you can see there's a pattern in your dataset.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Chieh Cheng Lai: And then this is where you can.
Soon | NTU: proceed with the next step. Is it really true that the number are… the data points are casted like this?
Soon | NTU: You know, what makes him stand out?
Soon | NTU: Why is it so different from this? Okay, so that is the next step. You will need to do analysis on your data point, detailed analysis.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, thank you.
Soon | NTU: You're welcome.
Soon | NTU: Over to you, Yumi.
germayne: Oh, okay, I think, I think just want to double-check, right, Kendra, Chacheng. I think your question is why they plotted using the two variables, correct?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, yes, they are using different…
germayne: Okay, the… I think the takeaway is that when you cluster, right, in the clustering algorithm, you can actually do it on n dimension.
germayne: You don't have to do it on… so in this original data, there's four dimensions, right? But obviously, when you want to visualize it, you can only choose two.
germayne: That's why it's just choosing any of the two variables, but the cluster that is done is using the four variables.
germayne: It's in 4 dimension.
germayne: Does that, does that make sense?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, yeah, it makes sense. It, it, no, just now, my concern is, the… the ship for the chemis and
Chieh Cheng Lai: this hierarchical clustering there looks different. So, actually, so my… my concern is the… because the variable we are using are different.
Chieh Cheng Lai: And then, that… that's what my concern is, but your… your explanation also correct, because, actually, there are four dimensions, we can't view it, and then somehow they translated into, different,
Chieh Cheng Lai: two-dimensional, but the variable that we are seeing here is different from the above one. That's… that might concern our heart.
germayne: No, but the, the, the…
germayne: the mapping is already done from the algorithm, right? Every point already has a group. What you are doing here is you're only visualizing it. What I choose as X and Y doesn't affect the color, or the group.
Chieh Cheng Lai: No, no, no, no, that's why I say there is a three distinct cluster… three cluster over here. That's… that's why, that's why some, soon also I spread, there is no, obviously overlapping, for example, the yellow and the green cluster compared to the above,
Chieh Cheng Lai: the camine cluster rate.
germayne: Okay, okay. Yeah, but it's just because the algo itself is different. That's why the clusters are different. But again, right, I think just to close this, this is just a toy data that you have to label. When you do clustering, you won't have this clear label.
germayne: Right? For everyone. This is just a toy… this is just a toy example. You have very clear segregation on the whys.
germayne: For each of the flower types.
germayne: But you… it won't be like that. You won't have the label to know that, oh, okay, is it like that. It doesn't… it doesn't work that way in real data. And you can use, hypothetically, a lot more data, which is why, I think, as explained above, some people, they choose to visualize using some kind of transformation that aggregates the features.
germayne: Right? You want to reduce the dimension, because you can also argue that maybe if I'm just plotting
germayne: one of the variables against the other, I might not be able to represent the data well.
germayne: Right, that's why we talk about visualizing using the dimension reduction.
germayne: Okay, okay, I think your question is answered right?
germayne: Okay, okay, yup, then, okay, then let's, let's, soon, can I share?
germayne: Let me share my screen.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so… you guys can see, right?
germayne: Okay, so what do you… what do you guys learn today?
germayne: What's an important takeaway today?
germayne: Okay, yep.
germayne: We will… we will come back to dimension reduction
germayne: To some extent, when we talk about deep learning next week.
germayne: Not explicitly, but I'll show you guys how it actually can also reduce dimension.
germayne: Yeah, so… Clustering and feature transformation, essentially, is what we've gone through today.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Any other takeaway for today?
germayne: Nope.
germayne: Oh, yes, also, yeah, there's also dbscan, yep.
germayne: Like, A's notes. What does that mean?
germayne: I see what, A levels? Is that the A?
germayne: What does the A means?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: beaten.
germayne: Huh?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Alvin's notes.
germayne: Oh, oh, okay.
germayne: Okay, so apparently the spam is good, I guess.
germayne: It's very abusive.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, can we move?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Sorry, for the Kaggle, can we use the DB scan?
germayne: Okay, and anything that we talk about today, you guys can try out.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Okay.
germayne: Okay, but, but, the other groups.
germayne: Okay, so if you guys see, right, you guys are actually very close, at least the top four. You are, like, essentially in 1200 decimal place.
germayne: So you guys are very, very close. For the other group, I think maybe you guys are busier, but I'm pretty sure you guys can also fight.
germayne: With the leaderboard, okay? So there's a motivation for the first place, only for first place.
germayne: Okay? Okay, let's continue.
germayne: Okay, so today, which one do you guys think is actually challenging?
germayne: Which concept do you think is challenging? Or today?
germayne: Oh, you guys start to find it easier.
germayne: Things are getting easier.
germayne: After we have a huge Load of topic last week.
germayne: I think it's easier, right? It's less… Less, less,
germayne: Inertia. Okay.
germayne: Oh, you guys find clustering concept difficult?
germayne: But maybe, can you guys explain what do you mean by that?
germayne: Since the algorithm is difficult, or is the application difficult?
Chieh Cheng Lai: the application.
germayne: Application, right, yeah.
germayne: But I think the, the, the point is that
germayne: there's no clear… because you can't evaluate. So it's actually very similar to statistical inference.
germayne: Where it's hard because now you don't have… you don't have an exact way to measure. Actually, clustering varies, but it is not useful because it has nothing to do with sometimes what you want to get out of the cluster, so there's no point for us to go through.
germayne: Right? But there are also metrics to measure, but…
germayne: not guaranteed to be correct as well. So I think it's hard, yes, right? So you have to choose based on what is the outcome that you want.
germayne: From the cluster, yeah. Noel.
germayne: And Noel asked challenging questions.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Actually, I thought coming to unsupervised would be much easier than supervised, but it seems like.
germayne: But the algo is easier, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, Outlook is easier, the understanding is easier, but maybe, like, what, Chachin is saying is really the application, because
Low Keng Teck, Noel: it's like, you try to, like, you know, you come from supervised already, until you got some idea, but now you have… now it comes to unsupervised, you talk, like, maybe the term is the wrong term, like, unsurvised is the wrong term to use, because, you know, yeah, this formula, the impression that when it comes to unsupervised, right, it should be much easier, but it turns out, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: How come it's, like, a different thing? It's like… it's not the exact opposite of survivorism, actually, counting of it. It's, like, another all over, another all totally new
Low Keng Teck, Noel: concept all over again, yeah. So, making use of it is really a challenge. I was like, or no Y. I thought, easier, but it's not.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. I think, I think you guys start to get a sense of…
germayne: it's not just… so the thing about data science is it's not just a job where you just take your notebook and then you just go and apply, apply, like, all the algo that you know. It doesn't work that way. A lot of it is, like, a detective work. You're, like, doing some kind of investigation, right? You have to really think.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, it's a FDA.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This topic is, like, really EDA.
germayne: Exactly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And I'm more ED?
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So, so, the… what is… and again, I've emphasized this to you, right, that…
germayne: the… what makes the job valuable is the insights that you're going to provide, and when or what to apply. I think that is what is hard.
germayne: Correct? So it's not… it's not so much about, like, today you have everything, and again, again, I like to use the analogy of, like, a culinary school, right? If you go and learn how to cook.
germayne: They are not going to teach you how to become a Michelin chef.
germayne: Right, so… A lot of it is, like, the art, when to apply something.
germayne: How do you apply something? Yeah?
germayne: Yeah, so correct, the application for today is hard. Okay, then let's talk about what actually was the easy part. I assume it's the algorithm, right? The algorithms are actually easy to understand.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'm like, shoot.
germayne: Correct. Or maybe because you guys are just better now.
germayne: Maybe it's not easier, it's just that you guys are better.
germayne: Maybe familiar to you, because I keep doing all the math, right? Actually, I toned down a lot already, just saying.
germayne: Today, the PCA, right?
germayne: A perfect way to do all the math.
germayne: So what do you guys, what do you guys think went well?
germayne: the algorithms.
germayne: Hmm. Yeah, I think perhaps you guys are very used to it.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Hmm, hmm. Yeah, I think it's a training that you guys have.
germayne: So moving forward, I think it should be easier and easier, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, I think we change up a bit of the sequence. I think maybe you guys might like this sequence better, so I think we break up into notebook to change the pace.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think for the last one, what do you guys think would be an area of reflection
germayne: For today's lesson.
germayne: What would be the takeaway?
germayne: Okay, I think I like how you guys, yeah, it's a good thing, it's a good thing.
germayne: Good thing.
germayne: Okay, but the takeaway is it's not just for Kaggle, by the way, because the Kaggle problem statement is more on prediction, so it will be useful, but it is in a different manner, okay? You'll be thinking more about, feature engineering.
germayne: Okay, so I think don't, don't worry too much, just continue in your free time.
germayne: to try your best, right? Don't waste the 5 submissions.
germayne: And on Saturday, I will maybe share a bit more tips in general for the groups.
germayne: Okay? But yes, how to apply to business, I think, is a good way to think about, and you have to try it empirically, and see what is the challenge.
germayne: Basically, you need to apply, and basically try to see if you're able to get any insights. Okay?
germayne: And if you have any questions, you can ask us.
germayne: Okay, yes, yes, I think you guys start to realize that actually the domain knowledge is very important, correct? Which is why I think… I believe I told some groups about this triangle. Good data science.
germayne: in terms of the discipline is, good programming, good math, intuition, and the last is actually business no-being. It's useless even if you do not know the business, okay? So, yes, I think… I hope that is a good takeaway, and unsupervised actually should emphasize that the business no-man is super important.
germayne: Okay, I think with that, right, what we will do is we will close for today. I think we exceeded a bit, yeah, but on Thursday, we will stop with all of these supervised and unsupervised, we will talk a bit about time series, okay? Time series prediction has a module, it's actually
germayne: a module on its own. If you think about it, time series itself, you can read books.
germayne: just purely on time series. So we will only just really go through the basics, just for you guys to understand, when you think about supervised learning, when you think about prediction.
germayne: How does it… Changes if the data is a sequential data.
germayne: Right, so we'll just introduce that. You will learn a bit about statistical time series, some of the traditional stats model, and of course, I'll try to reference some textbooks if you are interested. I will still recommend some textbooks for you to read. I believe I will be… I have some good
germayne: X, good.
germayne: experiences to share, because I used to do a lot of time series, so can probably share some of the business domain, but again, I think we're only going to do some very basic time series, okay? And then, on Saturday, then, we can just discuss some of the Kaggle advice, and we would… we have some time to do the exercises.
germayne: Okay, all good?
germayne: Okay, so if there's no questions, then yeah, I think thank you, thank you to Elvin for sharing all his notes, right? And thanks also soon to share also the notebook. So we will close today, and I will see you guys on Thursday.
germayne: Okay, and good luck for your kegel.
germayne: I'm monitoring the leaderboard, so yeah, good luck to that, yeah.
Dr Alvin Ang(2nd device): Thank you very much, thank you very much. Thank you. Sorry, sorry for spamming us, sorry, yeah, sorry. Sorry.
germayne: Okay, good night, everyone. If you guys got any questions, can stay back and ask, but if not, good night, good night.
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you.
germayne: See you guys on Thursday. Yeah, bye-bye, bye-bye.
Edwin Yap: Jamin.
germayne: Yeah, yes, Erie.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, just a quick one. Just now you mentioned about to scale or not to scale, so it's…
Edwin Yap: So, it's best not to scale, right?
germayne: No, it's to scale.
Edwin Yap: To scale first, right? Okay. I just want to clarify on that, as well.
germayne: Thank you, thank you.
Edwin Yap: Thank you.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Alright, Jermaine.
germayne: Hey, yes, Daniel.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Yeah, hi, just wanted to find out from you, order…
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): For the clinical competition, can you use what you thought today, is it? The…
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. Today, if you feel unsupervised, can help in your features, you guys go ahead.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Also, can use what taught today to do the kegona?
germayne: Yes, but the algorithm that we taught today, PCA and all this, right, is not directly supervised, but you can use it to improve your features, yes.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Okay, okay, thank you so much.
germayne: Yep, yep.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Well, yeah, one last question. All the links that Alvin posted in the chat, can compile them and give it to us.
germayne: Okay, I'll… I will ask Alvin to share. Ken, can, yeah, no doubt that.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Musta.
Edwin Yap: Sorry to interrupt. Daniel, not to worry, because I was keeping track of whatever that was posted by Elvin, right? And one last question from Kendra. So I got them into one Word document, I'll post it into Discord so everyone can share.
germayne: Okay.
Edwin Yap: Forget it.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Thanks so much. Okay, thank you.
Edwin Yap: Why not?
germayne: Yeah, fantastic, fantastic. Thanks, thanks, thanks, Evan, yep.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Yeah, thanks, Seriously.
Edwin Yap: No problem. It's sharing for everyone. And yeah, I think feature engineering, like what Daniel said, I think it's helpful. Just now you're trying to give us some hints, like, the effects of… we are just doing feature engineering, and then determining the why. So the why is, like, is there a hint given to us?
Edwin Yap: Yeah, that wouldn't.
germayne: Now, I think… I think you guys, the group, if I believe, if I remember correctly, you guys are doing well, don't have to worry so much. Now it's just iterating within your team to see how can… can you do better, yeah.
Edwin Yap: Ken. Okay, I don't want to hold you back. Thank you, everyone, good night.
germayne: Good night, good night.
Soon | NTU: Hi, everyone.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Aggie.
Soon | NTU: Hey, good night, Dwayne.
germayne: Yeah, goodnight, goodnight, goodnight, bye-bye.